<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nsis Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/nsis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nsis Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/nsis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with nsis</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/getting-started-with-nsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/getting-started-with-nsis/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # NSIS installer can be downloaded from http://nsis.sourceforge.net/Download. An exe of 1.6 MB will be downloaded. You can install it using the wizard. While installing there are options to install
1. Full: Installs all the components 2. Lite: Basic and only essential components from the UI 3. Minimal: The NSIS core files only. 4. Custom: It&#39;s up to us to install whichever components that we need. Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registering Libraries (RegDLL)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/registering-libraries-regdll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/registering-libraries-regdll/</guid>
      <description>In short, a DLL is a collection of small executable code, which can be called upon when needed by a program that&amp;rsquo;s running. The DLL lets the executable communicate with a specific device such as a printer or may contain code to do any number of particular functions. As there are several methods of implementations to do this, in this topic I&amp;rsquo;ll be showing you how to register and unregister any DLL that your application calls for; and we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing so using the RegSrv32.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DotNET</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/dotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/dotnet/</guid>
      <description>When the .NET Framework is being installed on a computer the .NET installer writes registry keys when installation is successful. You can test whether the .NET Framework 4.5 or later is installed by checking the registry key HKLM\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\NET Framework Setup\NDP\v4\Full for a DWORD value named Release. The existence of this key indicates that the .NET Framework 4.5 or later has been installed on that computer.
.NET Values # Below is a chart that shows the versions number corresponding DWORD value in the Release key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/nsis/services/</guid>
      <description>When installing a new program or updating an installation, it&amp;rsquo;s good practice for you to stop an installed application and anything related with it before overwriting any of its files. The same goes for services. We need to be sure that the locally run service (if any) is stopped before we can install or upgrade our program. In this topic I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few macros ranging from creating a service to querying a service to removing one all together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
