<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zsh Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/zsh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zsh Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/zsh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with zsh</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/zsh/getting-started-with-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/zsh/getting-started-with-zsh/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Getting zsh # zsh is available on many UNIX-like platforms via their built-in package management systems. On the Debian and Ubuntu Linux distributions, zsh is available in the default package repositories and can be installed using:
$ sudo apt-get install zsh # or, on newer Ubuntu distributions $ sudo apt install zsh On RPM-based distributions, zsh is also often available in the default package archives and can be installed using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Main differences from bash</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/zsh/main-differences-from-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/zsh/main-differences-from-bash/</guid>
      <description>Aliases # Global aliases # In bash, aliases can only be placed at the beginning of of a command, but zsh supports aliases anywhere. If you place the following line in your $ZDOTDIR/.zshrc
alias -g G=&#39; | grep -i&#39; You can then run
cat haystack.txt G &amp;quot;needle&amp;quot; Suffix aliases (Added in zsh 4.2.x) # Suffix aliases allow you to tell zsh to open files with specify a program to open files with certain extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oh-my-zsh</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/zsh/oh-my-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/zsh/oh-my-zsh/</guid>
      <description>Oh-my-zsh is one of many configuration frameworks for interactive use of zsh (it is not relevant for writing zsh scripts). It can be useful if you&amp;rsquo;d like to start with an experienced user&amp;rsquo;s configuration.
Installation # Oh-my-zsh is a community-driven framework for managing your zsh configuration. It contains many plugins, which extend functionality, themes, which manage the appearance of the shell and the prompt, and helpful functions that will make your terminal much more powerful and customizable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
