<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ms-access Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ms-access/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ms-access Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ms-access/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with ms-access</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/getting-started-with-ms-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/getting-started-with-ms-access/</guid>
      <description>What is MS-Access and what do we use it for ? # Microsoft Access is an Application Generator for developing databases and data-driven applications, primarily for local use. Microsoft Access consists of two main elements:
A Relational Database Management System (RDBMS) that combines the Microsoft Jet Database Engine (Access 2003 and earler) or the Access Database Engine (Access 2007 and later; see below) with graphical management tools. A unique Linked Tables system allows remote tables to be treated as local.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to troubleshoot Access crashes</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/how-to-troubleshoot-access-crashes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/how-to-troubleshoot-access-crashes/</guid>
      <description>When you receive an error: &amp;ldquo;Microsoft Access has encountered a problem and needs to close&amp;rdquo;, there is often not a lot of information to help you identify the cause of the error. Below are a series of steps you can take to troubleshoot the cause of the errors.
Be sure to remove other variables from the equation while testing
Network Corruption
Do not load the client off of a network. Put it on the local drive and run it from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/access-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/access-sql/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Access SQL # When using Access you can retrieve data using queries. These queries are built using Structured Query Language (SQL). Understanding SQL is important because it can help build better, more useful queries.
When creating queries in Access, you can switch to &amp;ldquo;SQL View&amp;rdquo;. An example of a &amp;ldquo;select&amp;rdquo; query is shown here:
Union (Merge) Queries # When you wish to combine the results of multiple tables or queries with similar fields together into a single resulting data set without performing any relational joins (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Referencing tables</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/self-referencing-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/self-referencing-tables/</guid>
      <description>In the example above, a reference field (SupID) can be used to indicate the ID of that employee&amp;rsquo;s supervisor.
Using something as simple as a DLOOKUP can return the name of that supervisor.
eg. DLOOKUP(&amp;quot;Name&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;EmployeeTable&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;ID = &amp;quot; &amp;amp; SupID)
Another good example of this is to look at how automated Access switchboards are created, and more specifically the construct of the Switchboard table. Each switchboard option refers to another option within the same table - similar to how this example self references.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parameterized Queries</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/parameterized-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ms-access/parameterized-queries/</guid>
      <description>Parameterized Queries can be used to defend against SQL Injection attacks.
Vulnerable Approach: Concatenated SQL string with form references # This is the typical approach for novice developers building SQL action queries. They are vulnerable to the Bobby Tables type SQL Injection attacks.
Dim strSQL As String strSQL = &amp;quot;INSERT INTO Employees chrFirstName, chrLastName, chrPhone &amp;quot; _ &amp;amp; &amp;quot;VALUES (&#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; Me!txtFirstName &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;,&#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; Me!txtLastName &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;,&#39;&amp;quot; &amp;amp; Me!txtPhone &amp;amp; &amp;quot;&#39;);&amp;quot; CurrentDb.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
