<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webrtc Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/webrtc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webrtc Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/webrtc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with webrtc</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/webrtc/getting-started-with-webrtc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/webrtc/getting-started-with-webrtc/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a WebRTC-based communication system # To setup a WebRTC-based communication system, you need three main components:
A WebRTC signaling server
To establish a WebRTC connections, peers need to contact a signaling server, which then provides the address information the peers require to set up a peer-to-peer connection. Signaling servers are for example:
signalmaster: Lightweight, JavaScript-based signaling server NextRTC: Java-based signaling server Kurento: Comprehensive WebRTC framework Janus: General purpose WebRTC Gateway A WebRTC client application</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC simple examples</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/webrtc/webrtc-simple-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/webrtc/webrtc-simple-examples/</guid>
      <description>Parameters # getUserMedia() Paramters Description Constraints It consist of array which allows us to specify which media devices to use i.e audio or video or both Success callback Create a function for success callback which will provide you the stream which you get from your media devices Error callback This callback get invoked when there is problem like there are no media devices, or user has denied the permission to use them Get camera and microphone permission and display preview on webpage # In order to begin using WebRTC you need to get camera and microphone permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using getUserMedia() to request camera and microphone access</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/webrtc/using-getusermedia-to-request-camera-and-microphone-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/webrtc/using-getusermedia-to-request-camera-and-microphone-access/</guid>
      <description>Using getUserMedia() # As we knew, WebRTC is all based on the JavaScript development and coding and for more information and examples please refer here and here.
And now, let me show you a very simple example to use getUserMedia();
For what getUserMedia() is used? # getUserMedia() is used to get the user/visitor&amp;rsquo;s camera and microphone detection.
Supported browsers for getUserMedia() # Mozilla Firefox 22 (PC) or higher.
Microsoft Edge 21 (PC) or higher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
