<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wolfram-mathematica Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/wolfram-mathematica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wolfram-mathematica Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/wolfram-mathematica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with wolfram-mathematica</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/wolfram-mathematica/getting-started-with-wolfram-mathematica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/wolfram-mathematica/getting-started-with-wolfram-mathematica/</guid>
      <description>What is (Wolfram) Mathematica? # Wolfram define Mathematica as &amp;ldquo;The world&amp;rsquo;s definitive system for modern technical computing&amp;rdquo;. A bold statement which is partially true. It&amp;rsquo;s probably not the most predominant (as you have to pay quite a bit for commercial use) system so people use Python or R for example. What it is, is the most comprehensive environment for &amp;ldquo;technical computing&amp;rdquo; by providing the follow functionality:
The Wolfram Language: A multi-paradigm language which covers symbolic computation with procedural, functional, list and rule-based programming &amp;ldquo;Notebooks&amp;rdquo;: A combination of documentation, programs and results Wolfram Algorithmbase: Probably the largest curated set of algorithms covering most major areas of mathematics, computation, and graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation Order</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/wolfram-mathematica/evaluation-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/wolfram-mathematica/evaluation-order/</guid>
      <description>This is supposed to explain the evaluation order as unambiguously as possible. It is probably less ideally suited as an introduction to Mathematica execution. It builds on Mathematica&amp;rsquo;s tutorial/Evaluation page by explaining the order in which different rules are applied and explaining which functions are treated specially by the evaluation engine.
Evaluation Contexts # At any point, code is executing within a context. A context consists of a set of replacement rules (its dictionary), and a priority in which they should be evaluated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
