<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>outlook-vba Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/outlook-vba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in outlook-vba Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/outlook-vba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with outlook-vba</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/getting-started-with-outlook-vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/getting-started-with-outlook-vba/</guid>
      <description>Introduction # There are currently three topics introducing Outlook VBA and at least three more are planned.
Part 1 describes how to get access to the Visual Basic Editor.
If you are a user of Outlook 2003 and a user of Excel VBA, you will learn little for this part since accessing the Outlook Visual Basic Editor is the same as accessing the Excel Visual Basic Editor.
With Outlook 2007 and later, the Developer tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction Part 3 Stores and all their folders</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/introduction-part-3-stores-and-all-their-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/introduction-part-3-stores-and-all-their-folders/</guid>
      <description>Completes the introduction to stores and folders started in part 2 of this tutorial
Expected prior knowledge: You have studied part 2 of this tutorial or are already familiar with its contents.
3. 0 Contents # How to reference any accessible folder. How to get the full name of a referenced folder. A pair of routines that together will list every folder within every accessible store. A routine to move a folder from one parent folder to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction Part 2 Stores and top-level folders</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/introduction-part-2-stores-and-top-level-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/introduction-part-2-stores-and-top-level-folders/</guid>
      <description>First part of an introduction to stores and the folders they contain. Contains macros to display (1) the names of accessible stores and (2) the names of accessible stores and the top level folders within them.
2.1 Expected prior knowledge # You are an Outlook user and understand terms such as “email”, “received time”, “subject” and “Folder Pane”. You know how to access Outlook’s Visual Basic Editor and create a module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction Part 1 Gaining access to Outlook&#39;s Visual Basic Editor</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/introduction-part-1-gaining-access-to-outlooks-visual-basic-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/outlook-vba/introduction-part-1-gaining-access-to-outlooks-visual-basic-editor/</guid>
      <description>Gaining access to Outlook&amp;rsquo;s Visual Basic Editor, inserting your first module and renaming that module.
Expected prior knowledge: You are an Outlook user.
With Outlook 2003, you can immediately select the Visual Basic Editor. With later versions, you must add the Developer tab before you can select the Visual Basic Editor.
1.3 Getting started with the Visual Basic Editor # The images in this section are all from Outlook 2016 but they could have come from Outlook 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
