<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>angular-cli Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/angular-cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in angular-cli Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/angular-cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with angular-cli</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/angular-cli/getting-started-with-angular-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/angular-cli/getting-started-with-angular-cli/</guid>
      <description>Generating and serving an Angular project via a development server # To create a new project ng new [project-name] which initializes git.Install packages for tooling via npm. It creates the project successfully.
cd [project-name] and execute either npm start or ng serve
It&amp;rsquo;ll run the server in the given default port.
Application will refresh according to the changes made in the directory. The default HTTP port and the one used by the LiveReload server can be changed using below command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with angular-cli Generating components, directives, pipes, services, etc.</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/angular-cli/working-with-angular-cli-generating-components-directives-pipes-services-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/angular-cli/working-with-angular-cli-generating-components-directives-pipes-services-etc/</guid>
      <description>The angular-cli tool can help you to scaffold different parts of an angular application (components, directives, pipes, services, classes, guards, interfaces, enums and modules).
Syntax # ng generate [component | directive | service | pipe | class | enum | interface | guard | module] [name] [flags&amp;hellip;] ng g [c | d | s | p | cl | e | i | g | m] [name] [flags&amp;hellip;] Parameters # Parameter Description component or c Used to generate component directive or d Used to generate directives service or s Used to generate services pipe or p Used to generate pipes class or cl Used to generate classes enum or e Used to generate enums interfaces or i Used to generate interfaces guard or g Used to generate guards module or m Used to generate modules --flat or -f Used to enable/disable directory creation --inline-template or -it Used to enable/disable inline html templates in components --inline-style or -is Used to enable/disable inline styles in components --prefix or -p Used to disable or change prefix --spec or -s Used to enable/disable .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>angular-cli project deployment on apache tomcat 8.0.14 server</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/angular-cli/angular-cli-project-deployment-on-apache-tomcat-8014-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/angular-cli/angular-cli-project-deployment-on-apache-tomcat-8014-server/</guid>
      <description>This topic would cover how angular-cli project is ready for production build, what all necessary steps taken before deploying, how to create war file for project deployment and finally how to configure the apache tomcat for angular-cli project deployment.
Neccessary steps taken before deploying the angular-cli project for production build. # Before deploying the angular project in server we need to build angular project for production. We also need to change the routing path in index.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
