<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>http-headers Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/http-headers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in http-headers Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/http-headers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with http-headers</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/getting-started-with-http-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/getting-started-with-http-headers/</guid>
      <description>HTTP Request # A simple HTTP Request for the resource /index.html. The host www.example.com is specified in the HTTP Host header.
GET /index.html HTTP/1.1 Host: www.example.com HTTP Response # A possible response to the request above. The response contains the HTTP headers Date, Content-Type, Content-Encoding and Content-Length.
HTTP/1.1 200 OK Date: Wed, 21 Jun 2017 10:58:03 GMT Content-Type: text/html; charset=UTF-8 Content-Encoding: UTF-8 Content-Length: 150 &amp;lt;response body&amp;gt; The response body is sent after the headers, separated by a blank line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Request-ID</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/x-request-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/x-request-id/</guid>
      <description>The X-Request-ID header can be used to trace individual requests to a web service (such as a REST API) from the client to the server and its backends.
Syntax # X-Request-ID: &amp;lt; value &amp;gt; A Client can send an HTTP header X-Request-ID: some-value. The server should use the provided value and provide it in any requests that it makes to backend services for the purpose of serving the initial the request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept-Ranges (Response)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-ranges-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-ranges-response/</guid>
      <description>Accept-Ranges tells the client that this server will supports ranges for this resource (file).
Syntax # Accept-Ranges: RangeType Accept-Ranges: none Parameters # Parameter Description RangeType That type of ranges are supported. This is currently only bytes or none. none The server does not support ranges on this resource Accept-Ranges is part of the ranges system. The ranges system lets the client request only part of a file instead of having to download the whole file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept-Encoding (Request)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-encoding-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-encoding-request/</guid>
      <description>Accept-Encoding tells the server what encoding the client accepts. Encoding is mostly used for compression.
Syntax # Accept-Encoding: Encoding;QualityFactor Accept-Encoding: Encoding;QualityFactor, type;QualityFactor, type;QualityFactor, &amp;hellip; Parameters # Parameter Description Encoding The type of encoding to use. This can also be a * to say the client has no preference to what encoding to use QualityFactor The quality factor in the format ;q=0.8. If this is set to 0 then it means &amp;ldquo;not acceptable&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept-Language (Request)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-language-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-language-request/</guid>
      <description>Accept-Language tells the server what language (such as English) does the client accept.
Syntax # Accept-Language: Language;QualityFactor Accept-Language: Language;QualityFactor, Language;QualityFactor, &amp;hellip; Accept-Language: * Parameters # Parameter Description Language What language is acceptable. QualityFactor The quality factor in the format ;q=0.8 (optional) * Match any language Accept-Language takes a number of languages and includes an optional preference for which one the server should use. The language is one from the list of available at IANA Language Subtag Registry page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept (Request)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-request/</guid>
      <description>What Content-Type does the client accept.
Syntax # Accept: MIMEType/MIMESubtype;QualityFactor Accept: MIMEType/MIMESubtype;QualityFactor, MIMEType/MIMESubtype;QualityFactor, &amp;hellip; Parameters # Parameter Description MIMEType The first half of the mime type. This can also be a */* for all types MIMESubtype The second half of the mime type or a * for all sub types (ie image/*) QualityFactor The quality factor in the format ;q=0.8 (optional) The content types are MIME types (ie text/html) separated by comma with an optional quality factor (using a ;q=) that is used the clients preference for using this type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept-Charset (Request)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-charset-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/http-headers/accept-charset-request/</guid>
      <description>Accept-Charset tells the server what character sets the client accepts.
Syntax # Accept-Charset: type;QualityFactor Accept-Charset: type;QualityFactor, type;QualityFactor, type;QualityFactor, &amp;hellip; Parameters # Parameter Description type A character set name. This can also be a * for all character sets QualityFactor The quality factor in the format ;q=0.8 (optional) Accept-Charset takes a number of character sets and includes an optional preference for which one the server should use. The charset is one from the list of available charsets at IANA &amp;ldquo;Character Sets&amp;rdquo; registry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
