<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ipython Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ipython/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ipython Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ipython/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with ipython</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ipython/getting-started-with-ipython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ipython/getting-started-with-ipython/</guid>
      <description>Installation and Usage # Like the built-in python interactive shell, IPython is a REPL (Read-Evaluate-Print Loop) shell, with a variety of features that make it more pleasant to use for day-to-day Python development than the built-in REPL shell.
Installation # To install it:
pip install ipython Or, via Anaconda:
# To install into the active environment: $ conda install ipython # Or, to create a new environment with IPython installed: $ conda create -n &amp;lt;env_name&amp;gt; ipython Or, via Enthought Canopy:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magics</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ipython/magics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ipython/magics/</guid>
      <description>IPython extends Python with a set of commands called magics. These are special functions whose names start with a % that are recognized by the IPython shell. Magics whose name begins with just one % take as argument the rest of the line and are called line magics. Magics that begin with a double percent sign %% take a multi-line argument and are called cell magics.
The %timeit and %time magics # The %timeit magic runs the given code many times, then returns the speed of the fastest result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPython shortcuts, tips and tricks</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ipython/ipython-shortcuts-tips-and-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ipython/ipython-shortcuts-tips-and-tricks/</guid>
      <description>IPython (and the Jupyter Notebook) defines a special meaning for the underscore. It always contains the the most recent output. This comes in useful when processing data in multiple steps. This is demonstrated in the example above. To clean up the text, it is run through a few regular expressions and then normalized before being split. Outside of IPython, each result would have to be stored in a new variable or the steps nested.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
