<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiki Online Documentation on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wiki Online Documentation on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2018-2022 Wikiod.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>contact at wikiod.com </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:23:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/about/</guid>
      <description>WikiOD is a collaboration to build and share the highest quality wiki online documentation. Imagine if everyone on Earth had an expert tutor who could teach them all education related subjects. Eventually, our wikiod should contain accurate instructions on almost every imaginable topic.
By contributing your knowledge to WikiOD, you will be helping people all over the world learn something new.
Creative Commons Licensed # WikiOD licenses all content under a Creative Commons license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DCMA</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/dcma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:23:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/dcma/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the original logo of wikiod, all other published content, including text, pictures, audio, video, software, programs, and web page layout design, are created by registered users of the site, hosted or collected online. Most of the content in WikiOD was written, edited and maintained primarily by contributors.
Wikiod respects artist and content owner rights. It is our mission to cooperate with alleged infringement notices that comply with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act of 1998 (&amp;ldquo;DMCA&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimers</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/disclaimers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:23:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/disclaimers/</guid>
      <description>Copyright Information # In addition to the original logo of wikiOD, all other published content, including text, pictures, audio, video, software, programs, and web page layout design, are created by registered users of the site, hosted or collected online.
The content provided by wikiOD.com is only used for personal study, training or research. We cannot guarantee the correctness of the content. The risks associated with using the content of this site have nothing to do with this site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:23:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from wikiod.com (the &amp;ldquo;Site&amp;rdquo;). Wikiod.com respects and protects the privacy of all users who use it wikiod.com. This &amp;ldquo;Privacy Policy&amp;rdquo; is related to your use of wikiod.com, so we recommend that you read it completely to help you better protect your privacy.
Scope of application # This &amp;ldquo;Privacy Policy&amp;rdquo; applies to our platform services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Use</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/terms-of-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:23:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/terms-of-use/</guid>
      <description>Every site has its legal Terms of Use. The bottom of this page contains our &amp;ldquo;Terms of Use Agreement&amp;rdquo;. Before you read it, you might want to first review our plain English guidelines to the WikiOD community:
A civil group effort # WikiOD is a group effort to create a great resource: free how-to-program tutorials. You must expect your writing to be modified, criticized constructively, or improved by others. Changes should be viewed in the spirit of improvement and not as a criticism of your approach or capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
