<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xml Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/xml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xml Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/xml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with xml</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/getting-started-with-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/getting-started-with-xml/</guid>
      <description>Well-formedness # An XML document is a text file that conforms to the XML specification&amp;rsquo;s well-formedness rules. Such a conforming document is said to be well-formed (not to be confused with valid). XML is very strict with well-formedness in comparison to other languages such as HTML. A text file that is not well-formed is not considered XML and cannot be used by consuming applications at all.
Here are some rules that apply to XML documents:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/namespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/namespaces/</guid>
      <description>Element and attribute names in XML are called QNames (qualified names).
A QName is made of:
a namespace (a URI) a prefix (an NCName, NC because it contains no colon) a local name (an NCName) Only the namespace and the local name are relevant for comparing two QNames. The prefix is only a proxy to the namespace.
The namespace and prefix are optional, but the namespace is always present if the prefix is present (this is ensured at the syntactic level, so this cannot be done wrong).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building blocks</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/building-blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/building-blocks/</guid>
      <description>Attributes # Attributes are name-value pairs associated with an element.
They are represented by values in single or double quotes inside the opening element tag, or the empty element tag if it is an empty element.
&amp;lt;document&amp;gt; &amp;lt;anElement foo=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot; abc=&#39;xyz&#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-- some content --&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/anElement&amp;gt; &amp;lt;anotherElement a=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/document&amp;gt; Attributes are not ordered (unlike elements). The following two elements have the same sets of attributes:
&amp;lt;foo alpha=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot; beta=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;foo beta=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot; alpha=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; Attributes cannot be repeated in the same element (unlike elements).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTD</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/dtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/dtd/</guid>
      <description>XML Document Type Declaration commonly known as DTD is a way to describe precisely the XML language. DTDs check the validity of, structure and vocabulary of an XML document against the grammatical rules of the appropriate XML language. A DTD defines the structure and the legal elements and attributes of an XML document.
XML document with an internal DTD # A DTD is referred to as an internal DTD if elements are declared within the XML files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entities</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/entities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/entities/</guid>
      <description>From a storage perspective, an XML document is made of entities. One of the entities is the document entity, which is the main XML document itself.
Entities can be classified like so (tentatively sorted by descending order of usage):
document entity: this is the main XML file. internal general entities: this is the most common one besides the document entity, and the one most XML users are aware of. Often, the word entity is casually used for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML Schema</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/xml-schema/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/xml-schema/</guid>
      <description>XML Schema is commonly known as XML Schema Definition (XSD). It is used to describe and validate the structure and the content of XML data. XML schema defines the elements, attributes and data types.
An Example of XSD Document # An XSD that describe a contact information about a company is given below.
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:schema targetNamespace=&amp;quot;http://NamespaceTest.com/CommonTypes&amp;quot; xmlns:xs=&amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema&amp;quot; elementFormDefault=&amp;quot;qualified&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:element name=&amp;quot;contact&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:complexType&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:sequence&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:element name=&amp;quot;name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;xs:string&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:element name=&amp;quot;company&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;xs:string&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;xs:element name=&amp;quot;phone&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;xs:int&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/xs:sequence&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/xs:complexType&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/xs:element&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/xs:schema&amp;gt; In the above example the attributes in second line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escaping</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/escaping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/escaping/</guid>
      <description>Characters can be escaped in XML using entity references and character references, or CDATA sections.
XML pre-defines five entities:
Named entity Replacement text amp &amp;amp; quot &amp;quot; apos &#39; lt &amp;lt; gt &amp;gt; Consuming applications will not know whether each character has been escaped or not, and how.
Ampersand # The &amp;amp; character appears first in entity references and must be escaped in element content or in attribute content.
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML Catalogs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/xml-catalogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xml/xml-catalogs/</guid>
      <description>An XML catalog is made up of entries from one or more catalog entry files. A catalog entry file is an XML file whose document element is catalog and whose content follows the XML catalog DTD defined by OASIS at http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/entity/spec.html. Most of the elements are catalog entries, each of which serves to map an identifier or URL to another location.
Catalog entry to resolve DTD location # &lt;?xml version=&#34;1.0&#34;?&gt; &lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
