<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>unicode Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/unicode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in unicode Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/unicode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with unicode</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/getting-started-with-unicode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/getting-started-with-unicode/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Detailed instructions on getting unicode set up or installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characters can consist of multiple code points</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/characters-can-consist-of-multiple-code-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/characters-can-consist-of-multiple-code-points/</guid>
      <description>An Unicode code point, what programmers often think of one character, often corresponds to what the user thinks is one character. Sometimes however a “character” is made up of multiple code points, as the examples above show.
This means that operations like slicing a string, or getting a character at a given index may not work as expected. For instance the 4th character of the string &amp;quot;Café&amp;quot; is &#39;e&#39; (without the accent).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UTF-8 as an encoding way of Unicode</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/utf-8-as-an-encoding-way-of-unicode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/utf-8-as-an-encoding-way-of-unicode/</guid>
      <description>What is UTF-8?
UTF-8 is an encoding, which is variable-length and uses 8-bit code units - that&amp;rsquo;s why UTF-8. In the internet UTF-8 is dominant encoding (before 2008 ASCII was, ehich also can handle any Unicode code point.).
Is UTF-8 the same as Unicode?
&amp;ldquo;Unicode&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t an encoding - it is a coded character set - i.e. a set of characters and a mapping between the characters and integer code points representing them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English text is not ASCII only</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/english-text-is-not-ascii-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/unicode/english-text-is-not-ascii-only/</guid>
      <description>An assumption which pops up regularly is that when dealing with English text only, it’s unlikely to encounter characters outside the ASCII character set. To avoid problems with handling Unicode correctly, people are tempted to do things like stripping non-ASCII characters, or removing any accents on letters.
These examples show this assumption is wrong, and even for English text you should take care to handle Unicode characters correctly.
Diacritics # English text has the occasional diacritics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
