<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/getting-started-with-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>SD card Setup # Start by installing the OS on the MicroSD card, either NOOBS or Raspbian, both provided by the Raspberry Pi foundation, available on their site. NOOBS, which stands for New Out Of Box Software, is designed for beginners, and is the easiest to install on your SD card. You can either follow their official instructions, or see below.
Format the SD card with a single partition of FAT32, using either the system drive management tool or a third party tool, such as the SD Association&amp;rsquo;s SD Formatter 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a scan station with scanbd (Raspbian)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/create-a-scan-station-with-scanbd-raspbian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/create-a-scan-station-with-scanbd-raspbian/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and installation # The purpose of this documentation is to use a scanner without any user interface. A common use is to upload a PDF scanned file directly to Google Drive or Dropbox just by pressing scanner-buttons.
scanbd permits to trigger actions from the scanner buttons, it uses sane.
What make things a little bit trickier is that by polling the scanner, scanbd locks the device. As we also need to scan from local tools (like scanimage), we need to set a proxy that&amp;rsquo;s going to interrupt scandb from polling when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable SSH on Raspbian</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/enable-ssh-on-raspbian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/enable-ssh-on-raspbian/</guid>
      <description>Previous versions of Raspbian (prior to November 2016) had SSH enabled by default. They also had a default username (pi) and password (raspberry) this was done to make first time setup for new users easier. But this obviously represents a large security hole. The new release (November 2016) disables SSH by default, and will also display a warning if SSH is enabled without changing the the default password.
The contents of the ssh file do not matter - you can create an empty file like we did above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating systems</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/raspberry-pi/operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>This section contains information about various operating systems available for the Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s.
Raspbian # The most popular operating system for the Raspberry Pi is a Debian based Raspbian.
It is officially supported by the Raspberry Pi Foundation.
Raspbian can be downloaded from official Raspberry Pi site in one of two variants:
With desktop environment Lite- Minimal image Starting September 2016 Raspbian is shipped with PIXEL desktop environment (&amp;ldquo;Pi Improved Xwindows Environment, Lightweight&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
