<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>access-vba Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/access-vba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in access-vba Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/access-vba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with access-vba</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/getting-started-with-access-vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/getting-started-with-access-vba/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Detailed instructions on getting access-vba set up or installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Error Codes (Form.Error, DataErr)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/access-error-codes-formerror-dataerr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/access-error-codes-formerror-dataerr/</guid>
      <description>The most tricky part is finding description for error codes. This site has a most complete list of codes I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far.
Below you can find a copy cleaned of &amp;ldquo;@@@&amp;ldquo;s.
Error Number Error Description 3 Return without GoSub 5 Invalid procedure call or argument 6 Overflow 7 Out of memory 9 Subscript out of range 10 This array is fixed or temporarily locked 11 Division by zero 13 Type mismatch 14 Out of string space 16 Expression too complex 17 Can&amp;rsquo;t perform requested operation 18 User interrupt occurred 20 Resume without error 28 Out of stack space 35 Sub or Function not defined 47 Too many DLL application clients 48 Error in loading DLL 49 Bad DLL calling convention 51 Internal error 52 Bad file name or number 53 File not found 54 Bad file mode 55 File already open 57 Device I/O error 58 File already exists 59 Bad record length 61 Disk full 62 Input past end of file 63 Bad record number 67 Too many files 68 Device unavailable 70 Permission denied 71 Disk not ready 74 Can&amp;rsquo;t rename with different drive 75 Path/File access error 76 Path not found 91 Object variable or With block variable not set 92 For loop not initialized 93 Invalid pattern string 94 Invalid use of Null 96 Unable to sink events of object because the object is already firing events to the maximum number of event receivers that it supports 97 Can not call friend function on object which is not an instance of defining class 98 A property or method call cannot include a reference to a private object, either as an argument or as a return value 321 Invalid file format 322 Can&amp;rsquo;t create necessary temporary file 325 Invalid format in resource file 380 Invalid property value 381 Invalid property array index 382 Set not supported at runtime 383 Set not supported (read-only property) 385 Need property array index 387 Set not permitted 393 Get not supported at runtime 394 Get not supported (write-only property) 422 Property not found 423 Property or method not found 424 Object required 429 ActiveX component can&amp;rsquo;t create object 430 Class does not support Automation or does not support expected interface 432 File name or class name not found during Automation operation 438 Object doesn&amp;rsquo;t support this property or method 440 Automation error 442 Connection to type library or object library for remote process has been lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EnableDisable Shift Key on DB Open</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/enabledisable-shift-key-on-db-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/enabledisable-shift-key-on-db-open/</guid>
      <description>This code will turn off the capability for a user to hold down the Shift key when opening a database to skip the default form opening and allow the user access to the Navigation Pane and VB Editor. In DB’s that you do not want users to have access to either of these (along with disabling the use of Special Keys in the Current Database Options), this code will help to keep the database locked down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check if Table Exists in Current DB</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/check-if-table-exists-in-current-db/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/check-if-table-exists-in-current-db/</guid>
      <description>Simply place this code as a Public Module that can be called by any other procedure. When calling the code, add in the name of the table you want to look up within the parenthesis. The Code returns a True/False value on whether or not a table already exists. This is helpful when needing to determine if a table needs to be deleted/purged or if a table already exists before performing additional code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Text Delimited File in Access Vba</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/create-text-delimited-file-in-access-vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/access-vba/create-text-delimited-file-in-access-vba/</guid>
      <description>Some times you may need to create a delimited text file for various uses. The following example is one of many ways to help you do that. I have used a pipe (&amp;quot;|&amp;quot;) for my delimiter, to change that just change the assignment of the Sep variable. In my example I dump the recordset to an array, this is by no means the defacto approach, its just my go to. This can easily be done using the recordset itself as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
