<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>atom-editor Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/atom-editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in atom-editor Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/atom-editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with atom-editor</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/getting-started-with-atom-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/getting-started-with-atom-editor/</guid>
      <description>What is Atom? # Atom is a hackable text editor created by GitHub and developed on top of the Electron desktop application platform.
This means it can be used as a text editor for basic programming up to a full-sized IDE. It is also extremely customisable, it provides thousands of community-made packages (syntax highlighting, improved UX, etc.) and themes to suit everyone&amp;rsquo;s needs. It is also available on Windows, MacOS, and Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation and Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/installation-and-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/installation-and-setup/</guid>
      <description>To troubleshoot errors that occur with building from source, please view the build documents.
Installing Atom on Windows # Using the official installer # Download the installer from the official website. It will automatically add atom and apm (Atom Package Manager) to your %PATH% variable.
Building from source # Requirements:
Node.js 4.4.x or later Python 2.7.x 7zip Visual Studio (One of the versions below) Visual C++ Build Tools 2015 Visual Studio 2013 Update 5 (Express Edition or better) Visual Studio 2015 (Community Edition or better) Git Run the following commmands into Command Prompt:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Editing With Atom</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/basic-editing-with-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/basic-editing-with-atom/</guid>
      <description>Note, the icons used at the end of the Opening Files and Directories example are not part of Atom&amp;rsquo;s standard styling, but are the result of the file-icons styling package.
Interactive File Tree # In order to keep track of your projects&amp;rsquo; file structure, Atom, like many text editors and IDEs, uses a file tree model. These trees show the locations and names of your files and directory. To toggle the tree between visible and hidden, the keys Ctrl+\ may be used (⌘+\ for Mac OS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Themes and Packages</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/themes-and-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/atom-editor/themes-and-packages/</guid>
      <description>Atom&amp;rsquo;s packages allow you to customize the editor to your needs. This topic will explains how packages and themes are created, published, and installed.
Downloading and Installing Packages and Themes # To view your installed packages or themes, open settings with Ctrl+, and select either the &amp;ldquo;Packages&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Themes&amp;rdquo; tab in the left-hand navigation bar. Note, the packages or themes you installed from other publishers will show up under the &amp;ldquo;Community Themes&amp;rdquo; section and themes pre-installed with Atom will show up under the &amp;ldquo;Core Themes&amp;rdquo; section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
