<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sparql Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/sparql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sparql Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/sparql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with sparql</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sparql/getting-started-with-sparql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sparql/getting-started-with-sparql/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with a SPARQL Endpoint # A query engine is required in order to execute SPARQL queries over a dataset. Query engines may be embedded in applications, or accessed remotely. Remote access may be through a vendor-specific API, or through the SPARQL protocol if an implementation supports it. This documentation will not cover how to submit queries through specific vendor APIs.
SPARQL Endpoint implementations typically provide a user-friendly web interface for submitting queries and viewing their results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with language tags</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sparql/working-with-language-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sparql/working-with-language-tags/</guid>
      <description>Getting a language tag from a literal # Literals in RDF may be language tagged strings. These literals have a text part as well as a language tag. For instance, the literal &amp;ldquo;color&amp;rdquo;@en has the text part &amp;ldquo;color&amp;rdquo; and the language tag &amp;ldquo;en&amp;rdquo;. In a SPARQL query, use the lang function to get the language of a literal with a language tag. If a literal does not have a language tag, then lang returns the empty string, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with graphs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sparql/working-with-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sparql/working-with-graphs/</guid>
      <description>What is a Named Graph?
An internal database document identifier (name) used by a SQL-compliant RDBMS to partition storage of relations represented as RDF sentence/statement graphs.
Why are Named Graphs Important?
A Named Graph is like a page in a book (the database) that contains a collection of paragraphs (sentence collections). Thus, it provides a powerful mechanism for query scoping that negates the need to scope all database queries to the entire database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
