<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android-studio Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/android-studio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android-studio Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/android-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with android-studio</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/getting-started-with-android-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/getting-started-with-android-studio/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Windows # Verify that you have the correct JDK. You can check it by opening command prompt (press windows key and write cmd). In the command prompt type javac -version, this will show the current version of JDK installed on your matching or an error* if Java is missing. If the JDK is not available or the version is lower than 1.8, download the Java SE Development Kit 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Studio Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/android-studio-tips-and-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/android-studio-tips-and-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Emulator for testing # If there are no specific needs, choose x86_64 system images with Google APIs to create the emulator.
It works way faster than armeabi-v7a on intel x86 x64 based computers.
There are some SDK libraries compiled and designed with ARM architecture.
If you try to install them on Intel based emulators you&amp;rsquo;ll get an error message saying
&amp;ldquo;INSTALL_FAILED_NO_MATCHING_ABIS&amp;rdquo;
You can go for a 3rd party emulator like [Genymotion] 1 or Visual Studio&amp;rsquo;s standalone Android Emulator on such occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Studio optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/android-studio-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/android-studio-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Parameters # Parameter Detail Xms Initial memory allocate Xmx Max memory allocate Customize the VM Option # You can override the default vmoptions with your own personal settings by choosing Help &amp;gt; Edit Custom VM Options from the Android Studio toolbar. This will create a local copy which you are free to edit.
Alternatively, you can edit the default vmoptions directly using the paths given below. Note that this method is not recommended, and your changes may be overwritten when updating Android Studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Studio updates</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/android-studio-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/android-studio/android-studio-updates/</guid>
      <description>Updating Android Studio in Ubuntu # If you are able to download an update of Android Studio, but after it restarts nothing happens, check out the following example:
After the patch was downloaded and Android Studio closed, open the terminal Go to your android studio folder, e.g. cd ~/android-studio Go to bin subfolder: cd bin Make sure your studio.sh file has run permissions: chmod +x studio.sh Run Android Studio from here: .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
