<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/getting-started-with-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/getting-started-with-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # What is Ubuntu # Ubuntu is an open source software platform, but colloquially, when Ubuntu is referred to it&amp;rsquo;s mainly toward the Ubuntu operating system. Ubuntu is based on Debian and uses the same package management system (deb and apt).
Installation # So you want to give Ubuntu a try! That&amp;rsquo;s great. First off, let&amp;rsquo;s grab the Ubuntu .iso file that you&amp;rsquo;ll be needing to install the operating system on your system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Terminal commands</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/basic-terminal-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/basic-terminal-commands/</guid>
      <description>How to exract tar.gz/bz2/tbz files :
If Your File Extension is .tar.gz (or .tgz) use this command
tar xvzf file.tar.gz x: This tells tar to extract the files.
v: This option will list all of the files one by one in the archive. The “v” stands for “verbose.”
z: The z option is very important and tells the tar command to uncompress the file (gzip).
f: This options tells tar that you are going to give it a file name to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Server</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/apache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/apache-server/</guid>
      <description>Php 5.6 with Apache 2 Server on Ubuntu 16.04 # This tutorial will guide you through the process from scratch. Please note some preliminary notes about this particular setup, useful in case that you already have some requested package:
Is needed a version of php &amp;gt;=5.0 (I had troubles with php 7.0)
Is requested any version of perl
Is needed a version of Apache that supports php scripting
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install perl apache2 zip gzip tar sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ondrej/php sudo apt update sudo apt install php5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/networking/</guid>
      <description>Set proxy from CLI # If you need to add proxy of your network in a reboot-persistent way, edit:
sudo vim /etc/environment Press i and after the row with PATH variable insert:
http_proxy=http://&amp;lt;proxy_server&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/ https_proxy=http://&amp;lt;proxy_server&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/ ftp_proxy=http://&amp;lt;proxy_server&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/ Then press ESC, enter : and write wq! for save and exit from vim.
If you need to use wget, add the same three rows to (eventually uncommenting them inside the file):
sudo vim /etc/wgetrc Show network interfaces # If you want to show active network interfaces, type:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support lifespan</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/support-lifespan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/support-lifespan/</guid>
      <description>New versions of Ubuntu are released by Canonical every 6 months. Every two years, the release is a Long Term Support version.
Support lifespan
Normal release - supported for 9 months Long Term Support (LTS) release
• LTS releases for Ubuntu Desktop, Ubuntu Server, Ubuntu Core, and Ubuntu Kylin are supported for 5 years.
• LTS releases for Kubuntu, Xubuntu, Ubuntu MATE and Lubuntu are supported for 3 years. What support means</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Installation</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/software-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/software-installation/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # sudo apt-get install &amp;lt;package_name&amp;gt;
sudo apt-get install &amp;lt;package1_name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;package2_name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;package3_name&amp;gt;
apt-get [options] [-o config=string] [-c=cfgfile] command [pkg]
Parameters # Command Description update Used to re-synchronize the package index files from their sources. An update should always be performed before an upgrade or dist-upgrade. upgrade Used to install the newest versions of all packages currently installed on the system. install This option is followed by one or more packages desired for installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up SSL</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/set-up-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ubuntu/set-up-ssl/</guid>
      <description>a2ensite - a script that enables the specified site (which contains a block) within the apache2 configuration by creating symlinks within /etc/apache2/sites-enabled
apache2 - popular web server. Alternative web servers are tomcat, nginx, etc.
openssl - SSL works by using a private key to encrypt data transferred over an SSL-enabled connection, thus thwarting eavesdropping of information. Use openssl to generate keys and certificates.
vim - a popular text editor</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
