<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>terminal Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/terminal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in terminal Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with terminal</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/terminal/getting-started-with-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/terminal/getting-started-with-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Terminal does not require any setup or installation and can be found by default.
Mac OS
Terminal comes default in macOS, and can be found in the Applications directory (Applications &amp;gt; Utilities &amp;gt; Terminal.app).
Linux (Ubuntu)
To open up your terminal press CTRL + ALT + T. Or search in the unity dash.
Windows
Windows 10 supports bash terminal which can be installed in the developer edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Customization</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/terminal/terminal-customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/terminal/terminal-customization/</guid>
      <description>This topic contains information about customizing the look, feel, and functionality of Terminal.
Terminal is easy to customize. Most terminal customization is available through both Terminal &amp;gt; Preferences graphically, and by using terminal commands.
The terminal preferences window contains 4 tabs, which are explained below.
Terminal Customization Tabs # Found under Terminal &amp;gt; Preferences
General
In the general tab, you can chose which profile is opened when you start terminal. You can set &amp;ldquo;Shells open with&amp;rdquo; to chose which directory terminal opens to, or specify a command to run each time you open a new terminal window or tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Navigation</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/terminal/terminal-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/terminal/terminal-navigation/</guid>
      <description>This topic contains information about navigating throughout the filesystem using the terminal.
Basic Navigation Commands # Change Directory
Navigate to a directory
cd [directory] Example: Changing to the projects directory
username$ cd projects Navigate to the root directory (regardless of working directory)
cd / Navigate to the parent directory (the directory containing the working directory)
cd .. Navigate to the home directory
cd ~ Print Working Directory
Prints the path of the directory that you are working in</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
