<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FreeBSD Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/freebsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FreeBSD Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/freebsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/getting-started-with-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/getting-started-with-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # FreeBSD is known of its well-written handbook (link). The installation process is described in detail in the Chapter 2. Installing FreeBSD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build from source</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/build-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/build-from-source/</guid>
      <description>Examples below are not necessarily in the correct order. See the Remarks section below for more information on the whole process.
Overview of the whole process # Download the latest source code. Configure the kernel. Build the world and the kernel. Configure the root filesystem of your new FreeBSD. Install the world and the kernel. Get the number of processors # An easy way to speed up the process of building and installing the new system is to use more processors to increase the computational power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD Jails</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/freebsd-jails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/freebsd-jails/</guid>
      <description>Deploying jail # A jail is simply a chroot with strong isolation. So, if you want to create jail, you simply need to create an alternative root and starting a new jail in it.
Simple jail deployment from binaries # # create our alternative root path JAILROOT=&amp;quot;/path/to/my/jail&amp;quot; mkdir -p &amp;quot;${JAILROOT}&amp;quot; cd &amp;quot;${JAILROOT}&amp;quot; # get distribution from freebsd repository fetch http://ftp.freebsd.org/pub/FreeBSD/releases/amd64/11.0-RELEASE/base.txz # extract it in our alternative root tar xJvf base.txz # now we can launch our jail jail -c name=simplejail path=${JAILROOT} # to check if jail is up and running we use jls jls # now we can enter in our new jail jexec simplejail sh Simple jail deployment from source # # create our alternative root path JAILROOT=&amp;quot;/path/to/my/jail&amp;quot; mkdir -p &amp;quot;${JAILROOT}&amp;quot; # we need to build binaries from source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packages and Ports management</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/packages-and-ports-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/packages-and-ports-management/</guid>
      <description>Tips:
Remember to always check the /usr/ports/UPDATING file before upgrading. There might be some significant changes in programs you use or in their configuration which will break your current setup. Building and installing software # If you have found your software in the ports tree, now its the time to build it.
Simple build and install with manual configuration # cd /usr/ports/www/apache24 make make install Simple build and install with automatic configuration # cd /usr/ports/www/apache24 make BATCH=yes make install Getting Ports tree # Portsnap # portsnap fetch portsnap extract updating ports tree with portsnap # portsnap update schedule cron job for daily updates # 0 3 * * * root /usr/sbin/portsnap cron SVN # head # cd /usr/ports svnlite checkout https://svnweb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up the FreeBSD development environment</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/set-up-the-freebsd-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/freebsd/set-up-the-freebsd-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>ctags # ctags is a useful utility you can use to read and move around the source code more efficiently. The built-in ctags(1) however is not the Exuberant Ctags utility you might expect.
You can install Exuberant Ctags (exctags(1)) using either ports or pkg:
Build exctags(1) using ports # cd /usr/ports/devel/ctags/ &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install clean Download and install a prebuilt binary of Exuberant Ctags: # pkg install ctags Create the tag file # exctags -R </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
