<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bitbucket Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/bitbucket/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bitbucket Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/bitbucket/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with bitbucket</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/getting-started-with-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/getting-started-with-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with Bitbucket - Create an account # Create an account
Go to https://bitbucket.org/ Click on Get Started on the top right corner Enter your email address, and click continue Enter your full name, password and verification code. Then click Continue An email will be sent to you to verify that you created your account After that you have now an account on Bitbucket and you can login to it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add collaborators to a repository</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/add-collaborators-to-a-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/add-collaborators-to-a-repository/</guid>
      <description>How to add users and groups to an existing Bitbucket repository # Go to the Bitbucket repository you want to add users to. On the left, go to Settings (the last icon on the bottom left). Select Users and group access. Under Users, start typing the name or email address of the user whom you want to add. Select the privilege you want to grant that user (Read, Write or Admin).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Issue in Bitbucket</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/create-issue-in-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/create-issue-in-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>Enable issue tracker in Bitbucket # Go to the repository you want to create issue for, something like: https://bitbucket.org//&amp;lt;repo_name&amp;gt;/ Go to setting, left bottom corner Select Issue tracker under Issues Select the type of the issue tracker you want to enable (no issue tracking, private or public) Click save Now the issue tracker is enabled for your repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add comments to commits in Bitbucket</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/add-comments-to-commits-in-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/add-comments-to-commits-in-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>Adding comment to a commit in Bitbucket # Go to the repository, e.g.: https://bitbucket.org/username/repo_name/ On the left menu, choose commits Select the commit you want to add comments to On the selected files related to that commit, click on the small + sign appearing near the line numbers A small window will appear to enter the text Click comment </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a new repository</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/create-a-new-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/create-a-new-repository/</guid>
      <description>Create a new repository on Bitbucket website # Go to https://bitbucket.org/dashboard/overview Login to your Bitbucket account Choose repositories from the top menu, then choose Create Repository Choose the owner, enter the repository name and select if you want to have it public or private repository Choose the repository type (Git or Mercurial) Open the advanced settings, and enter the information that you find appropriate for your project Then select create repository Now you have a blank repository created for you</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import repository into Bitbucket</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/import-repository-into-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/import-repository-into-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>Import existing repository to Bitbucket # Go to the repository you want to clone (something like: https://bitbucket.org/username/repo) On the top menu, choose Repository -&amp;gt; Import repository In the Old repository section, enter the source (CodePlex, Git, Google Code, Mercurial, Source Code, Subversion) and the URL In the New repository section, enter the Owner, the repository name, the access level (note: each one of the sources in step 3 has different inputs that needs to be added, in our example, we are focusing only on Git)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branching in Bitbucket</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/branching-in-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/branching-in-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>Creating a branch in Bitbucket # Go to the repository, e.g.: https://bitbucket.org/username/repo_name/ On the left menu, choose branches On the right side of the branches page, select Create branch A popup window will appear, select Branch from and enter the new branch you want to create in the Branch name textbox Click create A new branch will be created
Delete a branch in Bitbucket # Go to the repository, e.g.:https://bitbucket.org/username/repo_name/ On the left menu, choose branches Select the branch you want to delete from the branches page Click on &amp;hellip; at the top right of the page, then click Delete branch A confirmation popup will appear, click Confirm </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clone existing repository</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/clone-existing-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/bitbucket/clone-existing-repository/</guid>
      <description>Cloning a Git repository # Go to the repository you want to clone (something like: https://bitbucket.org/username/repo) On the left side, click on &amp;hellip; and choose Clone A small window will appear, copy the url (something like: git clone https://hamzawey@bitbucket.org/hamzawey/vm_dop_experiment.git) Open a terminal window on the machine you want to clone that project to Navigate from the command line to the location you want to clone the project and enter the command copied in step 3 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
