<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web-services Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/web-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web-services Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/web-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with web-services</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/web-services/getting-started-with-web-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/web-services/getting-started-with-web-services/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Server side (Host Webservices) # Web services must be installed and running (deployed) in a web server as web application components. They can be part of a bigger application, or they can be deployed alone as they may compose a complete application.
It is responsibility of the server to forward an incoming HTTP request to the corresponding deployed application, and responsibility of the application to handle the request according to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Web Services programmatically using C#.net and Xamarin app development</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/web-services/calling-web-services-programmatically-using-cnet-and-xamarin-app-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/web-services/calling-web-services-programmatically-using-cnet-and-xamarin-app-development/</guid>
      <description>Here we will see Pro-grammatically calling and using web services in ASP.Net C# . For the purpose you will required to download following ddl which provides you many functions. Download ImportJson from https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B-2bGoHKJvnOckdPUHVjdFZTcFU
This article is very useful for those of you who are going to develop a project using ASP.NET C# Web services/ Web API Services. This article is also useful for those who are developing a project using Xamarin: Mobile App Development</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>asp.net web-services</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/web-services/aspnet-web-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/web-services/aspnet-web-services/</guid>
      <description>Web Service is an application that is designed to interact directly with other applications over the internet. In simple sense, Web Services are means for interacting with objects over the Internet. The Web serivce consumers are able to invoke method calls on remote objects by using SOAP and HTTP over the Web. WebService is language independent and Web Services communicate by using standard web protocols and data formats, such as</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
