<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with emacs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/getting-started-with-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/getting-started-with-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Detailed instructions on getting emacs set up or installed.
Official instructions are available on the GNU Emacs website.
Debian systems # On systems with the Debian package manager (such as Debian, Ubuntu, and Mint) Emacs can be installed via the simple command:
sudo apt-get install emacs For a bleeding-edge release one can use the following ppa:
sudo apt-add-repository ppa:ubuntu-elisp/ppa sudo apt-get install emacs-snapshot Build for source # If your debian based distro does not have the version of emacs you want you can build it from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starter Kits</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/starter-kits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/starter-kits/</guid>
      <description>Starter kits enable new users to start using Emacs quickly and avoid some of the setup hurdles that come from a mature system like Emacs &amp;ndash; one that has grown through decades of evolution and naturally has some historical quirks. Experienced users also benefit from having a kit configuration of extensions that are curated by others.
It requires considerable effort to maintain a set of packages and settings that will continue to work well together as packages improve (or bit-rot) over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Management</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/package-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/package-management/</guid>
      <description>Automatic Package Installation with use-package # ;; disable automatic loading of packages after the init file (setq package-enable-at-startup nil) ;; instead load them explicitly (package-initialize) ;; refresh package descriptions (unless package-archive-contents (package-refresh-contents)) ;;; use-package initialization ;;; install use-package if not already done (if (not (package-installed-p &#39;use-package)) (progn (package-refresh-contents) (package-install &#39;use-package))) ;;; use-package for all others (require &#39;use-package) ;; install your packages (use-package helm :ensure t) (use-package magit :ensure t) Automatic package installation on emacs start-up # ;; package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Keybindings</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/basic-keybindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/basic-keybindings/</guid>
      <description>Quit Emacs # You can quit Emacs with the following keybinding:
C-x C-c
Where C is the control key.
Suspend Emacs You can suspend Emacs using the following keybinding :
C-z It gets you back to your shell. If you want to resume your emacs session, enter fg in your terminal.
Abort current command # Often you will get into a state where you have a partially typed command sequence in progress, but you want to abort it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Many Variants Of Emacs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/the-many-variants-of-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/the-many-variants-of-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Most of this documentation implicitly or explicitly applies to GNU Emacs. This may be the most well known variant of Emacs, as well as the source of several forks, and the target of some merges.
This topic discusses some of the variants of Emacs one may encounter, and their primary differences from GNU Emacs.
Spacemacs # Spacemacs (http://spacemacs.org/) is a variant of Emacs that attempts to end the long-term conflict between Emacs and vim users, by making an Emacs that behaves like vim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magit</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/magit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/magit/</guid>
      <description>Magit is an interface to the version control system Git, implemented as an Emacs package. It allows you to interact with git in Emacs.
Magit is an interface to the version control system Git, implemented as an Emacs package. Magit aspires to be a complete Git porcelain. While we cannot (yet) claim, that Magit wraps and improves upon each and every Git command, it is complete enough to allow even experienced Git users to perform almost all of their daily version control tasks directly from within Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs nomenclature</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/emacs-nomenclature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/emacs-nomenclature/</guid>
      <description>Elements of the User Interface # Emacs&amp;rsquo;s user interface uses terms that were coined early and can be unsettling to users used to a more modern terminology.
Frame # In Emacs, what is otherwise called a window (the area of the display used by a program) is called a frame. Emacs starts using one frame, though additional frames may be created using C-x 5.
Window # A frame contains one or more windows (otherwise usually called panes), each showing the content of one buffer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org-mode</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/org-mode/</guid>
      <description>Org is a mode for keeping notes, maintaining TODO lists, and project planning with a fast and effective plain-text system. It also is an authoring system with unique support for literate programming and reproducible research.
org Mode official site
Markup syntax # Org provides a full markup language which helps structuring the document, and is reflected as accurately as possible when exporting to other formats (like HTML or LaTeX).
Structure # Document title # #+TITLE: This is the title of the document Sectioning # * First level ** Second level Lists # Ordered list (items can also be numbered like &#39;1)&#39;, with a perenthesis): 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage bookmarks within Emacs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/manage-bookmarks-within-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/manage-bookmarks-within-emacs/</guid>
      <description>How to bookmark frequently used files # Use the following commands to create bookmarks and access bookmarks from within Emacs.
Let us say that you are editing a file called foobar.org and suppose that you visit this file frequently to edit / view contents.
It would be convenient to access this file with couple of key strokes rather than navigate through the file structure (Dired) and visit the file.
Steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emacs has already very high quality, well organized documentation. why duplicate it?</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/emacs-has-already-very-high-quality-well-organized-documentation-why-duplicate-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/emacs/emacs-has-already-very-high-quality-well-organized-documentation-why-duplicate-it/</guid>
      <description>https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/index.html#Top
Keys # https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Keys.html#Keys
3 Keys
Some Emacs commands are invoked by just one input event; for example, C-f moves forward one character in the buffer. Other commands take two or more input events to invoke, such as C-x C-f and C-x 4 C-f.
A key sequence, or key for short, is a sequence of one or more input events that is meaningful as a unit. If a key sequence invokes a command, we call it a complete key; for example, C-f, C-x C-f and C-x 4 C-f are all complete keys.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
