<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pharo Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/pharo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pharo Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/pharo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with pharo</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/pharo/getting-started-with-pharo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/pharo/getting-started-with-pharo/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Easy Install
Go to http://pharo.org/download and select a fitting download and run it.
Details
There are a lot of different ways to install Pharo. Pharo itself consists of a vm and an image. In addition it needs its sources and plugins, and has some dependencies:
It is a cross-platform environment, running on OS-X (and iOS), Windows and several unix variants (a.o. Ubuntu and Android). It runs on a virtual machine that can run on several processor architectures (Intel, ARM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Class</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/pharo/creating-a-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/pharo/creating-a-class/</guid>
      <description>Creating a class in Pharo is as simple as sending subclass: message to another class object. But most of the classes are created and modified in a system browser (currently Nautilus).
Adding a class in a system browser # The most common way to add (and edit classes) in from the system browser In the Nautilus system browser have nothing selected or select a package (first column) or a class (second column).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaside</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/pharo/seaside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/pharo/seaside/</guid>
      <description>Seaside is a web framework for Pharo and other smalltalks. It is ideal for complex applications with a rich domain model.
Droppable # A Seaside component (subclass of WAComponent) needs to override #renderContentOn:. It is a smalltalk class that can use all the normal ways of structuring an application. Here it delegates to three different methods.
JQDroppableFunctionalTest&amp;gt;&amp;gt;renderContentOn: html self renderInstructionsOn: html. self renderInventoryOn: html. self renderSelectedOn: html As a parameter it gets a html canvas object that understands messages relevant to building up the html and javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
