<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cryptography Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/cryptography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cryptography Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with cryptography</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/cryptography/getting-started-with-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/cryptography/getting-started-with-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Introduction # Cryptography is the science of using mathematical constructs (codes) to make communication secure. The field of cryptography is a subset of the field of Information Security.
There are many cryptographic operations possible; some best known examples are:
Encryption : transforming a plaintext message into a ciphertext message so that the the message remains confidential Decryption : transforming a ciphertext message back into a plaintext message Secure hashing : performing irreversible (one-way) compression to create a statically sized, computationally distinct representation for a specific message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playfair Cipher</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/cryptography/playfair-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/cryptography/playfair-cipher/</guid>
      <description>The best-known multiple-letter encryption cipher is the Playfair, which treats digrams in the plaintext as single units and translates these units into ciphertext digrams The Playfair algorithm is based on the use of a 5 x 5 matrix of letters constructed using a keyword.
Example of Playfair Cipher Encryption along with Encryption and Decryption Rule # A keyword is &amp;ldquo;MONARCHY&amp;rdquo; then the matrix will look like The matrix is constructed by filling in the letters of the keyword (minus duplicates) from left to right and from top to bottom, and then filling in the remainder of the matrix with the remaining letters in alphabetic order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar cipher</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/cryptography/caesar-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/cryptography/caesar-cipher/</guid>
      <description>It is the simple shift monoalphabetic classical cipher where each letter is replaced by a letter 3 position (actual Caesar cipher) ahead using the circular alphabetic ordering i.e. letter after Z is A. So when we encode HELLO WORLD, the cipher text becomes KHOORZRUOG.
Introduction # The Caesar cipher is a classic encryption method. It works by shifting the characters by a certain amount. For example, if we choose a shift of 3, A will become D and E will become H.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
