<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>svn Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/svn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in svn Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/svn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with svn</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/svn/getting-started-with-svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/svn/getting-started-with-svn/</guid>
      <description>Committing your local changes to the repository # To publish the changes you made in your working copy, run the svn commit command.
IMPORTANT: Review your changes before committing them! Use svn status and svn diff to review the changes. Also, make sure you are in the correct path before performing a commit. If you updated many files across various directories, you should be at the appropriate level to include all of them beneath your location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branching, shelving and tagging in Apache Subversion</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/svn/branching-shelving-and-tagging-in-apache-subversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/svn/branching-shelving-and-tagging-in-apache-subversion/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # svn copy [BRANCH-FROM-URL] [BRANCH-TO-URL] -m &amp;lt;COMMIT-LOG-MESSAGE&amp;gt;
svn copy [^/PATH-TO-BRANCH-FROM] [^/PATH-TO-BRANCH-TO] -m &amp;lt;COMMIT-LOG-MESSAGE&amp;gt;
As you might have noticed, we use svn copy command to create branches, tags and shelves (we&amp;rsquo;ll skip mentioning tags and shelves in the next paragraphs). This is the same command used to copy items in your working copy and into the repository.
svn copy is used for branching because, branch is technically a copy of the source you copy from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administering SVN</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/svn/administering-svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/svn/administering-svn/</guid>
      <description>Create new user # To add user, use following command
htpasswd /etc/subversion/passwd user_name
Specify user_name with the username you wish to add in above command. It will prompt to provide password for the user.
If you are creating very first user, you need to add –c switch in above command, which will create the file.
htpasswd -c /etc/subversion/passwd user_name
You can check existence of the file or list of configured users using following command cat /etc/subversion/passwd</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
