<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HTML Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/html/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTML Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with HTML</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/getting-started-with-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/getting-started-with-html/</guid>
      <description>Hello World # Introduction # HTML (Hypertext Markup Language) uses a markup system composed of elements which represent specific content. Markup means that with HTML you declare what is presented to a viewer, not how it is presented. Visual representations are defined by Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) and realized by browsers. Still existing elements that allow for such, like e.g. font, &amp;ldquo;are entirely obsolete, and must not be used by authors&amp;rdquo;[1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input Control Elements</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/input-control-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/input-control-elements/</guid>
      <description>A key component of interactive web systems, input tags are HTML elements designed to take a specific form of input from users. Different types of input elements can regulate the data entered to fit a specified format and provide security to password entry.
Syntax # &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Parameters # Parameter Details class Indicates the Class of the input id Indicates the ID of the input type Identifies the type of input control to display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Information</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/meta-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/meta-information/</guid>
      <description>Meta tags in HTML documents provide useful information about the document including a description, keywords, author, dates of modifications and around 90 other fields. This topic covers the usage and purpose of these tags.
Syntax # &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;metadata name&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;pragma directive&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;value&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;encoding label&amp;quot;&amp;gt; The meta tag is an HTML tag used to set the metadata of the HTML document. Meta tags need to go in the head element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/tables/</guid>
      <description>The HTML &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; element allows web authors to display tabular data (such as text, images, links, other tables, etc.) in a two dimensional table with rows and columns of cells.
Syntax # &amp;lt;table&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt; &amp;lt;thead&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/thead&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tfoot&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tfoot&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;th&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; The various table elements and their content attributes together define the table model. The &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; element is the container element for table models/tabular data. Tables have rows, columns, and cells given by their descendants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classes and IDs</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/classes-and-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/classes-and-ids/</guid>
      <description>Classes and IDs make referencing HTML elements from scripts and stylesheets easier. The class attribute can be used on one or more tags and is used by CSS for styling. IDs however are intended to refer to a single element, meaning the same ID should never be used twice. IDs are generally used with JavaScript and internal document links, and are discouraged in CSS. This topic contains helpful explanations and examples regarding proper usage of class and ID attributes in HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/lists/</guid>
      <description>HTML offers three ways for specifying lists: ordered lists, unordered lists, and description lists. Ordered lists use ordinal sequences to indicate the order of list elements, unordered lists use a defined symbol such as a bullet to list elements in no designated order, and description lists use indents to list elements with their children. This topic explains the implementation and combination of these lists in HTML markup.
Syntax # &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt; ordered list items &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; unordered list items &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; list item (ordered and not) &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dl&amp;gt; description list items &amp;lt;/dl&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt; description list title &amp;lt;/dt&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dd&amp;gt; description list description &amp;lt;/dd&amp;gt; See Also</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchors and Hyperlinks</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/anchors-and-hyperlinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/anchors-and-hyperlinks/</guid>
      <description>Anchor tags are commonly used to link separate webpages, but they can also be used to link between different places in a single document, often within table of contents or even launch external applications. This topic explains the implementation and application of HTML anchor tags in various roles.
Syntax # &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;URL or anchor&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Link Text&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Parameters # Parameter Details href Specifies the destination address. It can be an absolute or relative URL, or the name of an anchor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctypes</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/doctypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/doctypes/</guid>
      <description>Doctypes - short for &amp;lsquo;document type&amp;rsquo; - help browsers to understand the version of HTML the document is written in for better interpretability. Doctype declarations are not HTML tags and belong at the very top of a document. This topic explains the structure and declaration of various doctypes in HTML.
Syntax # &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE [version-specific string]&amp;gt; The &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE&amp;gt; declaration is not an HTML tag. It is used for specifying which version of HTML the document is using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFrames</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/iframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/iframes/</guid>
      <description>Parameters # Attribute Details name Sets the element&amp;rsquo;s name, to be used with an a tag to change the iframe&amp;rsquo;s src. width Sets the element&amp;rsquo;s width in pixels. height Sets the element&amp;rsquo;s height in pixels. src Specifies the page that will be displayed in the frame. srcdoc Specifies the content that will be displayed in the frame, assuming the browser supports it. The content must be valid HTML. sandbox When set, the contents of the iframe is treated as being from a unique origin and features including scripts, plugins, forms and popups will be disabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/html/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/html/images/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Parameters # Parameters Details src Specifies the URL of the image srcset Images to use in different situations (e.g., high-resolution displays, small monitors, etc) sizes Image sizes between breakpoints crossorigin How the element handles crossorigin requests usemap Name of image map to use ismap Whether the image is a server-side image map alt Alternative text that should be displayed if for some reason the image could not be displayed width Specifies the width of the image (optional) height Specifies the height of the image (optional) Creating an image # To add an image to a page, use the image tag.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
