<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>excel Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/excel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in excel Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/excel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with excel</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/getting-started-with-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/getting-started-with-excel/</guid>
      <description>Examples of some basic Formulas available in Excel # Excel has many Formulas built right in. Here are a few examples of some of the basic Formulas that might be handy to know when getting started with Excel:
Important Note : The name and Syntax of these Formulas vary on the language of your Excel installation! For example this Function here :
in English : =left(&amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;,5)
Same in German: =links(&amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;;5)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLOOKUP</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/vlookup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/vlookup/</guid>
      <description>Searches for a value in the first column of a table array and returns a value in the same row from another column in the table array.
The V in VLOOKUP stands for vertical. Use VLOOKUP instead of HLOOKUP when your comparison values are located in a column to the left of the data that you want to find.
Syntax # VLOOKUP(lookup_value, table_array, col_index_num, range_lookup) Parameters # Parameter Description lookup_value The value you&amp;rsquo;re searching for in the left column of the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DATEDIF function</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/datedif-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/datedif-function/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # =DATEDIF(start_date,end_date,unit) Parameters # Unit Returns &amp;ldquo;Y&amp;rdquo; The number of complete years in the period &amp;ldquo;M&amp;rdquo; The number of complete months in the period &amp;ldquo;D&amp;rdquo; The number of days in the period &amp;ldquo;MD&amp;rdquo; The difference between the days in start_date and end_date. The months and years of the dates are ignored &amp;ldquo;YM&amp;rdquo; The difference between the months in start_date and end_date. The days and years of the dates are ignored &amp;ldquo;YD&amp;rdquo; The difference between the days of start_date and end_date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel best practice</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/excel-best-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/excel-best-practice/</guid>
      <description>Use Excel Tables # By selecting a matrix and choosing &amp;ldquo;Insert Table&amp;rdquo; from the menu, you create a table which allows you to pull and insert data in a structured way. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have named the table &amp;ldquo;SalesEvents&amp;rdquo; and given that the first (header) row reads &amp;ldquo;Salesperson&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Date&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Sales Amount&amp;rdquo;, you can calculate sales amount like this: =SUM(SalesEvents[Sales Amount]). Entering data at the bottom of the table automatically adds new rows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel rounding and precision</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/excel-rounding-and-precision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/excel-rounding-and-precision/</guid>
      <description>Several Excel formulas deal with rounding and precision of non-integer numbers. This is separate from using cell formatting that affects the display of numeric data. In some cases just using cell formatting is sufficient, but in complex calculations, strict rules for rounding and precision are required to obtain consistent and correct results.
Syntax # =ROUND(number, num_digits) =ROUNDUP(number, num_digits) =ROUNDDOWN(number, num_digits) =MROUND(number, multiple) =TRUNC(number, [num_digits]) =INT(number) =CEILING(number, significance) =FLOOR(number, significance) =EVEN(number) =ODD(number) =FIXED(number, [decimals], [no_commas]) Parameters # Parameters Details number number to be rounded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MATCH function</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/match-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/match-function/</guid>
      <description>(Optional) Every topic has a focus. Tell the readers what they will find here and let future contributors know what belongs.
Parameters # Parameter Description lookup_value The value you want to match. Can be either a fixed value, cell reference or named range. Strings may not exceed 255 characters (required) lookup_array The cell reference (or named range) that you want to search, this can either be a row or a column sorted in ascending order for default type 1 matches; desceding order for -1 type matches; or any order for type 0 matches (required) match_type Controls the way the search works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An easy process to convert Monthly to Quarterly data in Excel</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/an-easy-process-to-convert-monthly-to-quarterly-data-in-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/an-easy-process-to-convert-monthly-to-quarterly-data-in-excel/</guid>
      <description>A frequent desire is to convert monthly data into quarterly data format. One simple method is to 1) sum the appropriate months into quarterly sums, then 2) identify those months as quarters, and finally 3) filter the quarterly data out of your monthly data. Here&amp;rsquo;s a relatively quick and easy method illustrated through the following example:
An easy way to perform a sometimes tedious routine task: # If you have your data with each month of data arranged in rows like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUMPRODUCT function</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/sumproduct-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/sumproduct-function/</guid>
      <description>The SUMPRODUCT function multiplies corresponding components in the given arrays, and returns the sum of those products
Syntax # SUMPRODUCT(array1, [array2], [array3], &amp;hellip;)
The array arguments must have the same dimensions. If they do not, SUMPRODUCT returns the #VALUE! error value.
SUMPRODUCT treats array entries that are not numeric as if they were zeros.
Using SUMPRODUCT with boolean arrays # Consider the following ranges A1:A3 and B1:B3 as below =SUMPRODUCT(--(A1:A3=&amp;quot;c&amp;quot;),B1:B3) This will first manipulate (A1:A3=&amp;quot;c&amp;quot;) into the following array</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting unique cells</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/counting-unique-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/counting-unique-cells/</guid>
      <description>Using COUNTIF() # =SUMPRODUCT((A1:A100&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)/COUNTIF(A1:A100,A1:A100&amp;amp;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)) counts unique cell values within A1:A100, excluding blank cells and ones with an empty string (&amp;quot;&amp;quot;).
How does it do that? Example:
A1:A100 = [1, 1, 2, &amp;quot;apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;peach&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, -, -, -, ...] Adding &amp;amp;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; to the array is needed to turn blank cells (-) into empty strings (&amp;quot;&amp;quot;). Result:
A1:A100&amp;amp;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; = [&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;peach&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Array formulas</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/array-formulas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/excel/array-formulas/</guid>
      <description>Sum of Product of Ranges # In this example, the total cost of buying food items is found by taking the number of each item and multiplying it by its cost and then adding all those values together.
Instead of creating a separate column for Number times Price and then summing the values in that new column, we can calculate the total price directly using an array formula:
=SUM(B2:B6*C2:C6) Since this is an array formula, it must be entered using Ctrl+Shift+Enter in order for Excel to treat it as such (otherwise will return #VALUE!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
