<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ionic-framework Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ionic-framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ionic-framework Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/ionic-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with ionic-framework</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/getting-started-with-ionic-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/getting-started-with-ionic-framework/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # 1. Install the Ionic Framework and Cordova (since Ionic apps are based on Cordova) using npm (the Node Package Manager): # Make sure you have an up-to-date version of Node.js installed on your system. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Node.js installed, you can install it from here.
Also, for Mac users, having the latest Xcode version installed on your system brings to you command-line-tools and iOs Simulator, download here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between “ionic build” and “ionic prepare”?</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/whats-the-difference-between-ionic-build-and-ionic-prepare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/whats-the-difference-between-ionic-build-and-ionic-prepare/</guid>
      <description>ionic build vs ionic prepare # From the official documentation:
If you want to get advanced, you can also open up the project file for a specific platform by opening the required XCode or Android Eclipse project in platforms/PLATFORM inside the root of your project. Then, you can build and test from inside the platform-specific IDE. Note: if you go this route, I recommend still working inside of the root www folder, and when you&amp;rsquo;ve made changes to this folder, run the command: $ cordova prepare ios which will update the iOS specific project with the code from the www folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Ionic App in a Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/testing-ionic-app-in-a-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/testing-ionic-app-in-a-browser/</guid>
      <description>Testing of native device features like Camera, Vibration and others, many of which are found in the documentation of Ionic Native, cannot be done in the browser. This is an inherent limitation of the fact that Cordova, the platform on which Ionic depends to be able to access native Android, iOS, and Windows Mobile APIs of a device, cannot run on the browser.
One can work around this issue by mocking the functionality of the native plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Ionic App on Emulator or on your Phone</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/run-ionic-app-on-emulator-or-on-your-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/run-ionic-app-on-emulator-or-on-your-phone/</guid>
      <description>Run Ionic App on Emulator or on your Phone # 1. Add a platform target # iOS:
$ ionic platform add ios Android:
$ ionic platform add android Windows:
$ ionic platform add windows 2. Build your app # iOS:
$ ionic build ios Android:
$ ionic build android Windows:
$ ionic build windows Live Reload App During Development (beta) # The run or emulate command will deploy the app to the specified platform devices/emulators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Ionic with any database</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/connecting-ionic-with-any-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/connecting-ionic-with-any-database/</guid>
      <description>You can&amp;rsquo;t do it directly from Ionic framework # The thing is; you can&amp;rsquo;t connect Ionic to any database (MySQL, Postgres, MSSQL, &amp;hellip;) directly. The keyword here is directly.
No, there&amp;rsquo;s no workaround, no magic involved, it&amp;rsquo;s just not the way this is supposed to work. Ionic works on top of Angular and Angular is a frontend framework.
However, the way you should do it is that you basically create a (RESTful) API on your server side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic CSS components</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic-css-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic-css-components/</guid>
      <description>Ionic has a lot of great ready declared CSS components to make your life easier while coding your next hybrid mobile application. These components vary from a basic grid system to styling your forms. These components are in your use if you choose to install Ionic with the pre-set CSS stylesheets.
One of the basic functions that Ionic CSS brings to your hand is that it comes with a set of colors to start with, but as a general rule colors are meant to be overridden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic Cloud for Yeoman Ionic Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic-cloud-for-yeoman-ionic-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic-cloud-for-yeoman-ionic-projects/</guid>
      <description>Ionic Platform (Ionic Cloud) for Yo (Yeoman) Ionic Projects # Ionic Platform: # Build, push, deploy, and scale your Ionic apps, the easy way. # Title Description:
The Ionic Platform is a cloud platform for managing and scaling cross-platform mobile apps. Integrated services enable you and your team to build, deploy, and grow your apps efficiently.
Document Objective: Ionic Platform works well with the standard Ionic projects. But projects following any Non-standard Directory Structure may face a few hurdles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Ionic as a website</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/deploy-ionic-as-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/deploy-ionic-as-a-website/</guid>
      <description>Simply copy the www folder to your web server # Ionic 1.2 officially supports deployment as a website
If you&amp;rsquo;re not using any Cordova plugins then there is no problem (if you really wish to) to upload the contents of the www folder to your server, and woila - you&amp;rsquo;ll have the same app.
However, it is important to note that Ionic 1 never intended for such a use, and the users of your &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo; will have to have the newest browser in order to see the &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo; correctly (not broken down due to some feature that Ionic is using in either CSS or HTML that some older browsers do not support).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic - Analyze your app with jshint and gulp-jshint as part of your build process</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic---analyze-your-app-with-jshint-and-gulp-jshint-as-part-of-your-build-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic---analyze-your-app-with-jshint-and-gulp-jshint-as-part-of-your-build-process/</guid>
      <description>Linting your ionic app before running has huge advantages. It will analyse code for potential errors and save you tremendous amount of time.
What is linting and how to install the required packages? # &amp;ldquo;Linting is the process of running a program that will analyse code for potential errors.&amp;rdquo; - see What is &amp;ldquo;Linting&amp;rdquo;?
Your ionic app comes with a package.json file. Go to the root of you app in a Command Line/Terminal and install the following packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic Backend Services (ionic.io)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic-backend-services-ionicio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/ionic-framework/ionic-backend-services-ionicio/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and setup # The Ionic Platform offers a range of powerful, hybrid-focused mobile backend services and tools to make it easy to scale beautiful, performant hybrid apps, at a rapid pace.
In order to use Ionic Platform you need to have the [Ionic Framework installed][2].
1.) Registration ([sign-up][3])
You need to enter: name, username, company, phone (optional), email and password. After you receive confirmation email you may [log-in][4].
Welcome to Ionic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
