<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gnuplot Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/gnuplot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gnuplot Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/gnuplot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Gnuplot</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/getting-started-with-gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/getting-started-with-gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Gnuplot is a portable command-line driven graphing utility. This example will show how to setup gnuplot in the various platforms.
Windows # Download the latest version of the installer from gnuplot site.
Run the downloaded file and allow it to run as administrator if requested
On the setup window select the language and follow the instructions on screen.
(optional) During the installation you may select the gnuplot to be added to the PATH that will allow you to run commands from anywhere on the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit data with gnuplot</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/fit-data-with-gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/fit-data-with-gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>The fit command can fit a user-defined function to a set of data points (x,y) or (x,y,z), using an implementation of the nonlinear least-squares (NLLS) Marquardt-Levenberg algorithm.
Any user-defined variable occurring in the function body may serve as a fit parameter, but the return type of the function must be real.
Syntax # fit [xrange][yrange] function &amp;ldquo;datafile&amp;rdquo; using modifier via parameter_file Parameters # Parameters Detail Fitting parameters a, b, c and any letter that had not been used previously Use letters to represent parameters that will be used to fit a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using script files</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/using-script-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/using-script-files/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # gnuplot -c scriptfile ARG1 ARG2 &amp;hellip; Basic usage can be displayed by typing gnuplot -h
$ gnuplot -h Usage: gnuplot [OPTION] ... [FILE] -V, --version -h, --help -p --persist -d --default-settings -c scriptfile ARG1 ARG2 ... -e &amp;quot;command1; command2; ...&amp;quot; gnuplot 5.0 patchlevel 3 Simple script file # Gnuplot is able to generate a graphic from a script file which allows for a sequence of commands necessary to draw a graphic to be executed in sequence instead of type in manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic plotting of data files</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/basic-plotting-of-data-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/basic-plotting-of-data-files/</guid>
      <description>One of the main useful features of gnuplot is the possibility of plotting data files. Plotting a data file is really simple with gnuplot, actually, once you have opened the software from the terminal, you only need to digit the command plot &#39;file&#39; to get an automatic plot.
First of all, before plotting, you must be sure to be under the same directory where the data file is, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually get a warning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Plotting Styles</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/2d-plotting-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/gnuplot/2d-plotting-styles/</guid>
      <description>Selecting a plotting style # Explicite selection # A plotting style is usually selected using the with keyword, like
plot x with points This allows to use different plotting styles for every plot:
plot x with points, 2*x with lines Typing help with in the gnuplot command window gives a list of all available plotting styles.
Global plotting style selection # Plotting styles can also be set globally for all plot commands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
