<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sublimetext3 Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/sublimetext3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sublimetext3 Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/sublimetext3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with sublimetext3</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/getting-started-with-sublimetext3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/getting-started-with-sublimetext3/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Please note that continued use of Sublime Text requires that you purchase a license and you are asked to note the terms and conditions.
The process of installing Sublime Text is different for each platform, but in each case you need to visit the download page.
After installing ST3, it is common to install the package manager, Package Control.
Mac # For Mac, there is only one version of Sublime Text for OS X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Sublime 3 on CentOS 7  RHEL 7?</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/how-to-install-sublime-3-on-centos-7--rhel-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/how-to-install-sublime-3-on-centos-7--rhel-7/</guid>
      <description>Here are the steps: # Step 1: Download Sublime: You can either download from their website or use the wget as I did:
$ cd ~/Downloads ## On 32bit $ wget https://download.sublimetext.com/sublime_text_3_build_3126_x32.tar.bz2 ## On 64bit $ wget https://download.sublimetext.com/sublime_text_3_build_3126_x64.tar.bz2 Step 2. Extract Sublime package (example to /opt directory) You can store Sublime at any place you want. Here, I saved under /opt directory.
## On 32bit $ sudo tar -vxjf sublime_text_3_build_3126_x32.tar.bz2 -C /opt ## On 64bit $ sudo tar -vxjf sublime_text_3_build_3126_x64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Packages</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/essential-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/essential-packages/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s in my ST (Sublime Text) # Package Control - Download/Install this plugin to install and manage all your other plugins in sublime. Git - Keeps track of your git versioning system. Also enables you to execute some git commands from ST itself. GitGutter - With GitGutter, you can see which lines have been added, deleted or modified in the gutter. Emmet - Emmet is a useful plugin that saves time by making you write less, thus increasing your productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Control</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/package-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/package-control/</guid>
      <description>Package Control is a full-featured package manager that helps discovering, installing, updating and removing packages for Sublime Text.
Package Control is the Sublime Text package manager. It includes a list of over 2,500 packages available for install, and users can add any GitHub or BitBucket repository themselves. Once installed, packages are kept up-to-date automatically.
The example code creates the Installed Packages folder for you (if necessary), and then downloads the Package Control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>This is a really small part, but still essential if you want to be able to communicate efficiently with other people using Sublime Text 3.
More to come: settings, keymap, mousemap etc&amp;hellip;
Themes # A theme changes the global skin of Sublime Text 3. It changes the tabs, side bar, quick panels (goto, command palette), status bar, etc&amp;hellip;
Here&amp;rsquo;s a non-exhaustive list of themes (top 100):
Predawn Material Theme Theme - Spacegray Seti_UI Theme - Brogrammer Theme - Flatland Theme - Soda Note: the convention for the theme packages name is that they start with Theme -.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Shortcuts for Sublime Text 3</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/list-of-shortcuts-for-sublime-text-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/list-of-shortcuts-for-sublime-text-3/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of commonly-used shortcuts in Sublime Text version 3. If you know of others, feel free to suggest an edit but I&amp;rsquo;ll start it with [Windows] ones I know. There is a list of shortcuts in the sublime text docs (at http://docs.sublimetext.info/en/latest/reference/keyboard_shortcuts_win.html) however there is a note at the top of the page that some may not work [To my knowledge, the ones listed here work!]. Note also that the link links to OSX page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/build-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/build-systems/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # Build Systems are written in JSON, and have the file extension .sublime-build. Build Systems are output-only, meaning it is not possible to execute some code that will request user input using the build system. The code will just block waiting for input forever. To work around this, many people use a REPL plugin.
JSON keys:
shell_cmd specifies the exact command to run in the shell, and has support for variable placeholders (like ${file} that refers to the currently open file).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybindings</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/keybindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/sublimetext3/keybindings/</guid>
      <description>Keybindings are, as a lot of things in Sublime Text, JSON. Make sure you understand how to use them, they&amp;rsquo;re going to save you a lot of time!
Syntax # keys: [list] a list of keystroke to press command: [string] the command to run args: [dict] the argument to pass to the command context: [list] a list of checker that will tell if the shortcut is enabled Shortcuts have to be stored in a file called Default.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
