<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>netsuite Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/netsuite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in netsuite Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/netsuite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with netsuite</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/getting-started-with-netsuite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/getting-started-with-netsuite/</guid>
      <description>Eclipse SuiteCloud IDE Setup # Download and install the latest Eclipse IDE Install Eclipse one of two ways: Eclipse Installer Download the zip for your favorite package If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a preferred Eclipse package, Eclipse for JavaScript Developers is recommended Install SuiteCloud IDE plugin Once installation is complete, launch Eclipse Navigate to Help &amp;gt; Install New Software&amp;hellip; Click Add&amp;hellip; to add a new Update Site Name: SuiteCloud IDE Location: http://system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/governance/</guid>
      <description>Governance # &amp;ldquo;Governance&amp;rdquo; is the name given to NetSuite&amp;rsquo;s system for detecting and halting long-running, runaway, or resource-intensive scripts.
Each script type has governance limits that it cannot exceed, and there are four types of governance limits in place for each script type.
API usage limit Instruction Count limit Timeout limit Memory usage limit If a script exceeds its governance limit in any one of these four areas, NetSuite will throw an uncatchable exception and terminate the script immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Event Before and After Submit events</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/user-event-before-and-after-submit-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/user-event-before-and-after-submit-events/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # beforeSubmit(type) // Before Submit, 1.0 beforeSubmit(scriptContext) // Before Submit, 2.0 afterSubmit(type) // After Submit, 1.0 afterSubmit(scriptContext) // After Submit, 2.0 Parameters # Parameter Details SuiteScript 2.0 - scriptContext {Object} scriptContext.newRecord {N/record.Record} A reference to the record that is being read from the database. We can use it to modify the field values on the record scriptContext.oldRecord {N/record.Record} A read-only reference to the previous state of the record. We can use it to compare to the new values scriptContext.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Sublists</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/working-with-sublists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/working-with-sublists/</guid>
      <description>NetSuite Records are divided into Body fields and Sublists. There are four types of sublists: Static, Editor, Inline Editor, and List.
We are able to add, insert, edit, and remove line items using Sublist APIs.
For a reference on exactly which sublists support SuiteScript, see the NetSuite Help page titled &amp;ldquo;Scriptable Sublists&amp;rdquo;.
Sublist Indices # Each line item in a sublist has an index that we can use to reference it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script Type Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/script-type-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/script-type-overview/</guid>
      <description>You create SuiteScript customizations using an event-driven system. You define various types of Script records, each of which has its own unique set of events, and in your source file, you define functions that will be called to handle those events as they occur.
Scripts are one of the primary components with which you&amp;rsquo;ll design and build your applications. The goal with this article is merely to become acquainted with the Script types and events available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Event Before Load event</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/user-event-before-load-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/user-event-before-load-event/</guid>
      <description>Parameters # Parameter Details SuiteScript 2.0 - scriptContext {Object} scriptContext.newRecord {N/record.Record} A reference to the record being loaded from the database scriptContext.type {UserEventType} The action type that triggered this User Event scriptContext.form {N/ui/serverWidget.Form} A reference to the UI form that will be rendered SuiteScript 1.0 - type {Object} The action type that triggered this User Event form {nlobjForm} A reference to the UI form that will be rendered request {nlobjRequest} the HTTP GET request; only available when triggered by browser requests beforeLoad # The Before Load event is triggered by any read operation on a record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the NetSuite Records Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/using-the-netsuite-records-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/using-the-netsuite-records-browser/</guid>
      <description>Using the NetSuite Records Browser # The Records Browser defines the schema for all scriptable record types; it is an extremely critical reference tool for every SuiteScript developer. When you need to know how to reference a particular field on a specific record type in your script, the Records Browser is your guide.
Direct Link
Other Schema # You may also notice tabs at the top of the Records Browser for Schema Browser and Connect Browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting formula columns in saved searches</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/exploiting-formula-columns-in-saved-searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/exploiting-formula-columns-in-saved-searches/</guid>
      <description>Formula columns in saved searches can exploit many features of Oracle SQL and HTML. The examples show how these features can be used, as well as pitfalls to avoid.
Oracle SQL CASE statement in a Netsuite formula # Using a CASE statement, conditionally display an expression in the column based on values found in another column, a.k.a. “my kingdom for an OR”. In the example, the result is obtained when the status of the transaction is Pending Fulfillment or Partially Fulfilled:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Transaction Searches</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/understanding-transaction-searches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/understanding-transaction-searches/</guid>
      <description>A deep understanding of how Transaction searches function is crucial knowledge for every NetSuite developer, but the default behaviour of these searches, and controlling that behaviour, can be quite confusing initially.
References:
NetSuite Help page: &amp;ldquo;Using Main Line in Transaction Search Criteria&amp;rdquo; Filtering with Main Line # When we only want one result per transaction, that means we only want the Body, or Main Line, of each transaction. To accomplish this, there is a filter named &amp;ldquo;Main Line&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lookup Data from Related Records</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/lookup-data-from-related-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/netsuite/lookup-data-from-related-records/</guid>
      <description>When processing a given record, you will oft need to retrieve data from one of its related records. For example, when working with a given Sales Order, you may need to retrieve data from the related Sales Rep. In SuiteScript terminology, this is called a lookup.
Lookup functionality is provided by the nlapiLookupField global function in SuiteScript 1.0 and the N/search module&amp;rsquo;s lookupFields method in SuiteScript 2.0
Syntax # nlapiLookupField(recordType, recordId, columns); Parameters # Parameter Details recordType String - The internal ID of the type of record being looked up (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
