<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jersey Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/jersey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jersey Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/jersey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with jersey</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/getting-started-with-jersey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/getting-started-with-jersey/</guid>
      <description>CRUD Operations example in Jersey # This example demonstrates the use of GET, POST, PUT and DELETE HTTP Methods in doing CRUD operations on a REST resource
I am using the below software, frameworks and tools:
Jersey 2.25.1 JDK 1.7.x (Java 7) Eclipse IDE Kepler Apache Maven 3.3.9 Apache Tomcat 7.x Please follow the below steps for Creating the required Jersey Application
Step 1 : Create a new maven project using maven-archetype-webapp archetype in Eclipse IDE by choosing File-&amp;gt;New-&amp;gt;Maven Project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Injection with Jersey</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/dependency-injection-with-jersey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/dependency-injection-with-jersey/</guid>
      <description>Basic Dependency Injection using Jersey&amp;rsquo;s HK2 # Jersey (2) uses HK2 as its dependency injection (DI) system. We can use other injection systems, but its infrastructure is built with HK2, and allows us to also use it within our applications.
Setting up simple dependency injection with Jersey takes just a few lines of code. Let say for example we have a service we would like to inject into our resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Spring Boot with Jersey</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/using-spring-boot-with-jersey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/using-spring-boot-with-jersey/</guid>
      <description>Simple Application with Spring Boot and Jersey # Spring Boot is a bootstrapping framework for Spring applications. It has seamless support for integrating with Jersey also. One of the advantages of this (from the perspective of a Jersey user), is that you have access to Spring&amp;rsquo;s vast ecosystem.
To get started, create a new standalone (non-wepapp) Maven project. We can create a webapp also, but for this guide, we will just use a standalone app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jersey MVC Support</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/jersey-mvc-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/jersey-mvc-support/</guid>
      <description>MVC Frameworks such as Spring MVC are using to create web applications that serve dynamic web pages. Jersey, though known to be a REST Framework, also has support for create dynamic web pages using its MVC module.
Jersey MVC Hello World # To get started, create a new Maven webapp (how to do this is outside the scope of this example). In your pom.xml, add the following two dependencies
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring JAX-RS in Jersey</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/configuring-jax-rs-in-jersey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/jersey/configuring-jax-rs-in-jersey/</guid>
      <description>Java Jersey CORS filter for Cross Origin Requests # Java Jersey Configuration # This example illustrates how to configure Jersey so that you can begin using it as a JAX-RS implementation framework for your RESTful API.
Assuming that you have already installed Apache Maven, follow these steps to set up Jersey:
Create maven web project structure, in terminal (windows) execute the following command mvn archetype:generate -DgroupId= com.stackoverflow.rest -DartifactId= jersey-ws-demo -DarchetypeArtifactId=maven-archetype-webapp -DinteractiveMode=false</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
