<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GNULinux Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GNULinux Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with GNULinux</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/getting-started-with-gnulinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/getting-started-with-gnulinux/</guid>
      <description>Useful shortcuts # Using The Terminal # The examples in this document assume that you are using a POSIX-compliant (such as bash, sh, zsh, ksh) shell.
Large portions of GNU/Linux functionality are achieved using the terminal. Most distributions of Linux include terminal emulators that allow users to interact with a shell from their desktop environment. A shell is a command-line interpreter that executes user inputted commands. Bash (Bourne Again SHell) is a common default shell among many Linux distributions and is the default shell for macOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Linux distribution name and version</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/detecting-linux-distribution-name-and-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/detecting-linux-distribution-name-and-version/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # uname - to print information about your operating system.
uname [OPTION]
Detect what debian-based distribution you are working in # Just execute lsb_release -a.
On Debian:
$ lsb_release -a No LSB modules are available. Distributor ID: Debian Description: Debian GNU/Linux testing (stretch) Release: testing Codename: stretch On Ubuntu:
$ lsb_release -a No LSB modules are available. Distributor ID: Ubuntu Description: Ubuntu 14.04.4 LTS Release: 14.04 Codename: trusty In case when you don&amp;rsquo;t have lsb_release installed you may want to try some guessing, for example, there is a file /etc/issue that often contains distribution name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling the Linux kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/compiling-the-linux-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/compiling-the-linux-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of Linux Kernel on Ubuntu # Warning: be sure you have at least 15 GB of free disk space.
Compilation in Ubuntu &amp;gt;=13.04 # Option A) Use Git
Use git if you want to stay in sync with the latest Ubuntu kernel source. Detailed instructions can be found in the Kernel Git Guide. The git repository does not include necessary control files, so you must build them by:
fakeroot debian/rules clean Option B) Download the source archive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/shell/</guid>
      <description>The shell executes a program in response to its prompt. When you give a command, the shell searches for the program, and then executes it. For example, when you give the command ls, the shell searches for the utility/program named ls, and then runs it in the shell. The arguments and the options that you provide with the utilities can impact the result that you get. The shell is also known as a CLI, or command line interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Shell (SSH)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/secure-shell-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/secure-shell-ssh/</guid>
      <description>A secure shell is used to remotely access a server from a client over an encrypted connection. OpenSSH is used as an alternative to Telnet connections that achieve remote shell access but are unencrypted. The OpenSSH Client is installed on most GNU/Linux distributions by default and is used to connect to a server. These examples show use how to use the SSH suite to for accept SSH connections and connecting to another host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/network-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/network-configuration/</guid>
      <description>This document covers TCP/IP networking, network administration and system configuration basics. Linux can support multiple network devices. The device names are numbered and begin at zero and count upwards. For example, a computer with two NICs will have two devices labeled eth0 and eth1.
Interface details # Ifconfig
List all the interfaces available on the machine
$ ifconfig -a
List the details of a specific interface
Syntax: $ ifconfig &amp;lt;interface&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Compression with &#39;tar&#39; command</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/file-compression-with-tar-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/file-compression-with-tar-command/</guid>
      <description>Parameters # Common Options - -c &amp;ndash;create Create a new archive. -x &amp;ndash;extract Extract files from an archive. -t &amp;ndash;list List the contents of an archive. -f &amp;ndash;file=ARCHIVE Use archive file or dir ARCHIVE. -v &amp;ndash;verbose Verbosely list files processed. Compression Options - -a &amp;ndash;auto-compress Use archive suffix to determine the compression program. -j &amp;ndash;bzip2 Filter the archive through bzip2. -J &amp;ndash;xz &amp;ndash;lzma Filter the archive through xz. -z &amp;ndash;gzip Filter the archive through gzip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCP</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/scp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/scp/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # scp [-rv] [-i identity_file] [[user@]host1:]file1 &amp;hellip; [[user@]host2:]file2 Basic Usage # # Copy remote file to local dir scp user@remotehost.com:/remote/path/to/foobar.md /local/dest # Copy local file to remote dir scp foobar.md user@remotehost.com:/remote/dest # Key files can be used (just like ssh) scp -i my_key.pem foobar.md user@remotehost.com:/remote/dest Secure Copy # scp command is used to securely copy a file to or from a remote destination. If the file is in current working directly only filename is sufficient else full path is required which included the remote hostname e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Managers</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/package-managers/</guid>
      <description>How to update packages with the apt package manager # The Advanced Package Tool, aptly named the &amp;lsquo;apt&amp;rsquo; package manager can handle the installation and removal of software on the Debian, Slackware, and other Linux Distributions. Below are some simple examples of use:
update
This option retrieves and scans the Packages.gz files, so that information about new and updated packages is available. To do so, enter the following command:
sudo apt-get update</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting System Information</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/getting-system-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/linux/getting-system-information/</guid>
      <description>Collection of commands to fetch system related information.
Statistics about CPU, Memory, Network and Disk (I/O operations) # To get general statistics about main components of Linux family of stat commands are extremely useful
CPU # To get processors related statistics you can use mpstat command but with some options it will provide better visibility:
$ mpstat 2 10 Memory # We all know command free to show amount of (remaining) RAM but to see all statistic including I/O operations:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
