<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xsd Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/xsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xsd Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/xsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with xsd</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xsd/getting-started-with-xsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xsd/getting-started-with-xsd/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # XSD, XML Schema Definition, is a language which describes the structure of XML documents. XSD files can be used to validate an XML file. The process of doing this will depend on what you choose to implement it with. Care should be taken to ensure the validation engine you use is compatible with the desired version of XSD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xscomplexType</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xsd/xscomplextype/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xsd/xscomplextype/</guid>
      <description>A xs:complexType provides a description of an XML element&amp;rsquo;s content in the instance document. The definition of the xs:complexType can be made globally in which case it has a name and can be re-used within the schema, or it can be inplace and only used within the context it is declared.
Parameters # Attributes Description abstract When set to true the complex type can not be used directly in an instance XML document via xsi:type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xsschema</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/xsd/xsschema/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/xsd/xsschema/</guid>
      <description>Describes for elements, attributes and types that are valid in an XML instance document. An XML Schema (XSD) must contain a single root level xs:schema element.
Parameters # Attributes Description attributeFormDefault Indicates whether attributes in the XML instance document have to be qualified with a namespace (default unqualified) blockDefault The default value of the block attribute that is applied to xs:complexType and xs:element. Defines the rules for blocking derivation/substituion in the instance document (default empty, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
