<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yaml Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/yaml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in yaml Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/yaml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with yaml</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/yaml/getting-started-with-yaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/yaml/getting-started-with-yaml/</guid>
      <description>Comments # # This comment occupies a whole line - some item # This comment succeeds content of a line - http://example.com/#nocomment - &amp;quot;This # does not introduce a comment.&amp;quot; - | This is a block scalar. A # inside it does not introduce a comment. # unless it is less indented than the first line (this is one) Note that for a # to introduce a comment, it must either</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using anchors and aliases for transcluded content</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/yaml/using-anchors-and-aliases-for-transcluded-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/yaml/using-anchors-and-aliases-for-transcluded-content/</guid>
      <description>Creating an &amp;ldquo;Array of Dictionaries&amp;rdquo; table with YAML anchors as row identifiers # --- person_table: - &amp;amp;person001 fname: homer lname: simpson role: dad age: 33 - &amp;amp;person002 fname: marge lname: simpson role: mom age: 34 - &amp;amp;person003 fname: peter lname: griffin role: dad age: 34 Problem # developer wishes to express a table structure in YAML, where each row is referenced by a compact row identifier Solution # use YAML anchors, by assigning an anchor identifier to each row in the table in YAML, reusable &amp;ldquo;transclusion identifiers&amp;rdquo; are called anchors and aliases in YAML, reusable &amp;ldquo;transclusion identifiers&amp;rdquo; consist of alphanumeric tokens preceeded by an ampersand or asterisk Rationale # YAML anchors and aliases allow for increased data normalization YAML anchors and aliases enforce DRY (Don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself) in this example, a table structure can be designed and preserved which closely coincides with a database Pitfalls # YAML anchors must be declared before they can be referenced by aliases YAML anchors must be unique throughout the document failure to specify unique anchors will cause an error on yaml.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
