<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>amazon-ec2 Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/amazon-ec2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in amazon-ec2 Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/amazon-ec2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with amazon-ec2</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/getting-started-with-amazon-ec2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/getting-started-with-amazon-ec2/</guid>
      <description>EC2 Instances # Detailed instructions on launching an EC2 instance.
Launching an EC2 Instance with the AWS Management concole # In this example, we will launch a basic EC2 Instance with Amazon Linux in the quickest manner possible via the AWS Management Console. Amazon frequently improves the user experience of the AWM Management console, so you might experience some changes to the screens below.
Important: launching an instance in this manner is not considered secure and can incur cost if the instance is left running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/introduction-to-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/introduction-to-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Installing the aws cli # On linux: If you don&amp;rsquo;t have pip installed, install it first:
curl &amp;quot;https://bootstrap.pypa.io/get-pip.py&amp;quot; -o &amp;quot;get-pip.py&amp;quot; sudo python get-pip.py Then install awscli:
sudo pip install awscli On Windows: Download the latest installers from here
Configuring the aws cli # Now you have aws cli installed, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to configure it access your AWS resources. You can have multiple profiles like test, dev, prod, etc profiles. So let&amp;rsquo;s assume you want to configure it for your test environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using aws-cli for Amazon EC2</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/using-aws-cli-for-amazon-ec2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/using-aws-cli-for-amazon-ec2/</guid>
      <description>Getting information about EC2 instances # You can obtain information about EC2 instances using:
aws ec2 describe-instances You can obtain information about specific EC2 instances using:
aws ec2 describe-instances --instance-ids ... where ... contains one or more instance identifiers. For example:
aws ec2 describe-instances --instance-ids i-abcdefgh i-ijklmnop The output of aws ec2 describe-instances uses pagination by default. If the response contains the key &amp;quot;NextToken&amp;quot; then you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use that token to obtain the next page of information:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Keys for Amazon EC2 instances</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/ssh-keys-for-amazon-ec2-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/amazon-ec2/ssh-keys-for-amazon-ec2-instances/</guid>
      <description>Securing your SSH private key # An SSH key has two pieces, the public key and the private key.
The private key:
Is usually in a file named id_rsa, but it can be given any name. CANNOT BE REGENERATED IF LOST!!!! Do not lose this file! If you lose it, you will not be able to get back into your instance. (StackOverflow is littered with questions by people who have done this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
