<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>npm Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/npm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in npm Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/npm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with npm</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/getting-started-with-npm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/getting-started-with-npm/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Install # npm is bundled with Node.js, so if you install Node.js you&amp;rsquo;ll automatically have npm installed too. You can choose between a Current and a LTS version
Windows # For Microsoft Windows you can download a MSI installer from https://nodejs.org/en/download/.
OS X # For Apple OS X you can download a PKG installer from the same location https://nodejs.org/en/download/.
Linux # For Linux you can use your package manager to install Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/publishing/</guid>
      <description>Publish public repository # To publish public repositories with a free npm account, you initially need to publish the module with access of public. One way to do this is to set the config for npm to read in packages.json as follows:
&amp;quot;publishConfig&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;access&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;public&amp;quot; }, you can also use the flag --access=public with the npm publish command. Otherwise you will get the slightly confusing error message, &amp;ldquo;you need a paid account to perform this action&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>npm scripts</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/npm-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/npm-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # The &amp;ldquo;scripts&amp;rdquo; property in package.json allows you to run npm packages locally. The &amp;quot;karma&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;karma&amp;quot; script references the karma shell script is the node_modules/.bin directory. This reference needs to be grab and an alias needs to be applied to it in order to be used in other npm scripts, such as &amp;quot;test&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;karma start&amp;quot;. Pre-recognized scripts # prepublish: Run before the package is published publish, postpublish: Run after the package is published preinstall: Run before the package is installed install, postinstall: Run after the package is installed preversion, version: Run before bump the package version postversion: Run after bump the package version pretest, test, posttest: Run by the npm test command prestop, stop, poststop: Run by the npm stop command prestart, start, poststart: Run by the npm start command prerestart, restart, postrestart: Run by the npm restart command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What NPM does ?</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/what-npm-does/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/npm/what-npm-does/</guid>
      <description>It allows you to easily manage different packages (modules) and keep track of which version you&amp;rsquo;ve installed.
Initialize a new NPM project # npm init This will initialize a new NPM project for you - just press enter until it stops asking you questions.
Now you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that you have a new file called package.json. This file will, among other things, keep track of which packages or modules you&amp;rsquo;ve installed in your project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
