<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google-analytics-api Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/google-analytics-api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google-analytics-api Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/google-analytics-api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with google-analytics-api</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/getting-started-with-google-analytics-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/getting-started-with-google-analytics-api/</guid>
      <description>Introduction # The Google Analytics APIs allow you to access data within Google Analytics. It should not be confused with the measurement protocol which is used for inserting data into Google Analytics.
The Google Analytics API is split into serval parts.
Google Analytics Reporting APIs
The Google Analytics Core Reporting API v3 gives you access to most of the report data in Google Analytics. With the Core Reporting API you can:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting API (Analytics v4)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/reporting-api-analytics-v4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/reporting-api-analytics-v4/</guid>
      <description>The Google Analytics Reporting API V4 is the most advanced programmatic method to access report data in Google Analytics. With the Google Analytics Reporting API, you can:
Build custom dashboards to display Google Analytics data. Automate complex reporting tasks to save time. Integrate your Google Analytics data with other business applications. Features
Google Analytics is built upon a powerful data reporting infrastructure. The Google Analytics Reporting API V4 gives you access to the power of the Google Analytics platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error Responses</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/error-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/error-responses/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # 400 invalidParameter Indicates that a request parameter has an invalid value.
400 badRequest Indicates that the query was invalid. E.g., parent ID was missing or the combination of dimensions or metrics requested was not valid.
403 insufficientPermissions Indicates that the user does not have sufficient permissions for the entity specified in the query.
403 dailyLimitExceeded Indicates that user has exceeded the daily quota (either per project or per view (profile)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time API</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/real-time-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/real-time-api/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # GET https://www.googleapis.com/analytics/v3/data/realtime?ids=[Analytics view Id]&amp;amp;metrics=[Real-time metrics]&amp;amp;access_token=[Access_token_from_Authentcation] GET https://www.googleapis.com/analytics/v3/data/realtime?ids=[Analytics view Id]&amp;amp;metrics=[Real-time metrics]&amp;amp;dimensions=[Real-time metrics]&amp;amp;access_token=[Access_token_from_Authentcation] Parameters # (Required) Parameter name Description ids Unique table ID for retrieving Analytics data. Table ID is of the form ga:XXXX, where XXXX is the Analytics view (profile) ID. metrics A comma-separated list of Analytics metrics. E.g., &amp;lsquo;rt:activeUsers&amp;rsquo;. At least one metric must be specified. (Optional) Parameter name Description dimensions A comma-separated list of real-time dimensions. E.g., &amp;lsquo;rt:medium,rt:city&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/authentication/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # GET https://accounts.google.com/o/oauth2/auth?client_id={clientid}&amp;amp;redirect_uri=urn:ietf:wg:oauth:2.0:oob&amp;amp;scope={Scopes}&amp;amp;response_type=code POST https://accounts.google.com/o/oauth2/token code={Code from above call}&amp;amp;client_id={ClientId}&amp;amp;client_secret={ClientSecret}&amp;amp;redirect_uri=urn:ietf:wg:oauth:2.0:oob&amp;amp;grant_type=authorization_code POST https://accounts.google.com/o/oauth2/token client_id={ClientId}&amp;amp;client_secret={ClientSecret}&amp;amp;refresh_token={From above call}&amp;amp;grant_type=refresh_token Parameters # Parameter Description Client Id From Google Developer console identifies your project or application secret From Google Developer console identifies your project or application redirect_uri From Google Developer location where the authentication should be returned to. In the case of Native applications urn:ietf:wg:oauth:2.0:oob can be used to denote localhost In order to access any Google API you need to identify yourself as a developer and identify your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata api</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/metadata-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics-api/metadata-api/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # HTTP GET https://www.googleapis.com/analytics/v3/metadata/{reportType}/columns?key={APIKey} HTTP GET https://www.googleapis.com/analytics/v3/metadata/{reportType}/columns?access_token={Access_token} Parameters # Parameter name Description reportType Report type. Allowed Values: ga. Where ga corresponds to the Core Reporting API. The Metadata API returns the list and attributes of columns (i.e. dimensions and metrics) exposed in the Google Analytics reporting APIs (v2,v3 and v4). Attributes returned include UI name, description, segments support, and more.
You can use the Metadata API to:
Automatically discover new columns Access all dimensions and metrics attributes for Google Analytics reporting APIs This is the same list as is in the Dimensions &amp;amp; Metrics Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
