<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google-analytics Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/google-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google-analytics Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/google-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with google-analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/getting-started-with-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/getting-started-with-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Getting on board with Google Analytics # Getting a GA Account: If you don’t have an Analytics account, create one. If you do have an Analytics account, sign in. Both options are available at google.com/analytics
Setting up a property in your Analytics account: A property represents your website or app where the data gets aggregated.
Create a view: Views let you create filtered perspectives of your data. When you create a property one view is created by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Tracking</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/event-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/event-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Below is the example of how to hard code the google analytics implementation in the website. To track the shopping cart actions let induce the tracking snippet. It look as below. You can track the events in google analytics open source tool
Syntax # ga(&#39;send&#39;, &#39;event&#39;, [eventCategory], [eventAction], [eventLabel], [eventValue], [fieldsObject]); Parameters # Field Name Description eventCategory Typically the object that was interacted with (e.g. &amp;lsquo;Video&amp;rsquo;) eventAction The type of interaction (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data processing latency</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/data-processing-latency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/data-processing-latency/</guid>
      <description>What is Data processing latency? # When a hit is sent to Google Analytics the data must be processed. Processing latency is 24-48 hours. This means that it can take time before you will see data under standard reports (Not real-time) any data that you do see may not be correct as it has probably not completed processing.
Standard accounts that send more than 200,000 sessions per day to Analytics will result in the reports being refreshed only once a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Google Analytics data in your Website</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/displaying-google-analytics-data-in-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/displaying-google-analytics-data-in-your-website/</guid>
      <description>Displaying Google Analytics data in your Website # This document explains how to get Google Access tokens and use them to get Google Analytics data to be displayed in our websites.
Example: A live example is available in
https://newtonjoshua.com
note: Use the same gmail account for all the below steps.
STEP 1: Set Up Google Analytics # Follow the below steps to set up Google Analytics in your website
Sign in to your Analytics account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging JavaScript errors within Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/logging-javascript-errors-within-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/logging-javascript-errors-within-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>The example above has two tracking events, Event Tracking and Exception Tracking.
Event Tracking will allow you to see JS errors in real-time. Under Real Time -&amp;gt; Events sections.
Unfortunately, your error messages will be limited by 500 Bytes, so you will not be able to understand a problem properly, however you will know that something is going wrong.
Exception Tracking will give you more detailed report, with full error message and browser information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/sampling/</guid>
      <description>Parameters # Parameter Details sampleRate Float number describing the amount of users in percent to be tracked. Default = 100. Sampling in Analytics is the practice of selecting a subset of data from your traffic and reporting on the trends available in that sample set. Sampling is widely used in statistical analysis because analyzing a subset of data gives similar results to analyzing all of the data. In addition, sampling speeds up processing for reports when the volume of data is so large as to slow down report queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create and manage goals</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/create-and-manage-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/google-analytics/create-and-manage-goals/</guid>
      <description>Smart Goals # In addition to the goal types described above, Analytics provides an alternative conversion tracking method called Smart Goals. Smart Goals are specifically designed to help AdWords advertisers who may not have enough conversions to use the AdWords optimization tools, such as automated bidding. When you have Smart Goals enabled, Analytics automatically evaluates your website or app visits and assigns each a score, with the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; visits being translated into Smart Goals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
