<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>processing Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in processing Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with processing</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/getting-started-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/getting-started-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>Hello World # The easiest way to write Processing code is to simply call a series of functions. Press the run button in the Processing editor, and Processing will run your code. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example:
size(200, 200); background(0, 0, 255); fill(0, 255, 0); ellipse(100, 100, 100, 100); This code creates a 200x200 window, draws a blue background, changes the fill color to green, and then draws a circle in the middle of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Processing with Alternative Code Editors like Sublime and Atom</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/using-processing-with-alternative-code-editors-like-sublime-and-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/using-processing-with-alternative-code-editors-like-sublime-and-atom/</guid>
      <description>Using Processing with Sublime Text # To add a language to Sublime Text, you use Package Control. You can do this by pasting the correct Python code (available on the Package Control site linked above), or by downloading the .sublime-package file (also available for download on the site). Once you set up Package Control, restart Sublime Text.
To install the Processing package from Package Control, follow the following steps:
Execute Tools | Install processing-java in order to install the processing-java tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Processing for Android</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/getting-started-with-processing-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/getting-started-with-processing-for-android/</guid>
      <description>You can find more information on Processing for Android at http://android.processing.org/
Installation # Before getting started on Processing for Android, make sure you have Processing installed.
Open Processing Click on Add Mode&amp;hellip; located in the top right of the window: Search for &amp;ldquo;android&amp;rdquo; in the Contribution Manager and choose the option that has the author &amp;ldquo;The Processing Foundation&amp;rdquo; and click Install Once the installation has been complete, switch the mode to Android This window below should pop up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic shapes and functions using P3D</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/basic-shapes-and-functions-using-p3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/basic-shapes-and-functions-using-p3d/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # translate(float x, float y, float z) rotateX(float angle) rotateY(float angle) rotateZ(float angle) box(float size) box(float w, float h, float d) Parameters # Parameters Details angle the angle is in radians size the dimension of the box to be used for all its dimensions w the dimension of the box in the x-axis h the dimension of the box in the y-axis d the dimension of the box in the z-axis 3D Translation # Here&amp;rsquo;s how to translate objects in P3D:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Basic Shapes</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/drawing-basic-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/drawing-basic-shapes/</guid>
      <description>In Processing, drawing shapes is key to the program. Otherwise, nothing would appear on the screen. This section will tell you how basic shapes are drawn.
Syntax # line(float x1, float y1, float x2, float y2) line(float x1, float y1, float z1, float x2, float y2, float z2) ellipse(float x, float y, float w, float h) rect(float x, float y, float w, float h) triangle(float x1, float y1, float x2, float y2, float x3, float y3) Parameters # Parameter Details x1 x-coordinate of the first point y1 y-coordinate of the first point z1 z-coordinate of the first point x2 x-coordinate of the second point y2 y-coordinate of the second point z2 z-coordinate of the second point x3 x-coordinate of the third point y3 y-coordinate of the third point x x-coordinate y y-coordinate w width h height You can find a reference on Processing&amp;rsquo;s foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Processing&#39;s P3D renderer</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/using-processings-p3d-renderer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/using-processings-p3d-renderer/</guid>
      <description>A reference for using P3D is found at https://processing.org/tutorials/p3d/ in a tutorial by Daniel Shiffman.
Getting Started # To be able to use the P3D renderer you must specify it in the size() function
size(200, 200, P3D); Now, there are three axes: x, y and z.
Now you can proceed in drawing in 3D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colours in Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/colours-in-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/processing/colours-in-processing/</guid>
      <description>This article will show you the various colours formats in Processing and the ways in which they can be used.
Syntax # color(r, g, b); color(r, g, b, alpha); color(gray); color(gray, alpha); color(h, s, l); //The mode must be HSB. You can change this using colorMode. Parameters # Parameters Details r Is the red of the color when the mode is RGB. g Is the green of the color when the mode is RGB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
