<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>api Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in api Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with api</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/api/getting-started-with-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/api/getting-started-with-api/</guid>
      <description>What is an API? # API: Application programming interface are the set of requirements which govern how one application can talk to another, API&amp;rsquo;s are what makes the information exchange between programs possible.
For Example System-level APIs makes it possible for applications like LibreOffice to run on top of an OS like Windows in the first place. On web API are responible to let other apps to piggyback to the large service proivder such as Google maps or Facebook offering(Services).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Api Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/api/api-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/api/api-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>These are some API Best Practices I had been used.
Parameters # Parameter Details sort Sort by Single or Multiple columns. sort=email,name dir Sort Ascending/Descending. dir=asc or dir=desc column Filter by. phone=5555555555 limit Items per Page. limit=25 page Page Number. page=2 api_key API Key. api_key=ABCDEF1234567890 Status Codes # 1xx: Information # Message Description Long Description 100 Continue The server has received the request headers, and the client should proceed to send the request body 101 Switching Protocols The requester has asked the server to switch protocols 103 Checkpoint Used in the resumable requests proposal to resume aborted PUT or POST requests 2xx: Successful # Message Description Long Description 200 OK The request is OK (this is the standard response for successful HTTP requests) 201 Created The request has been fulfilled, and a new resource is created 202 Accepted The request has been accepted for processing, but the processing has not been completed 203 Non-Authoritative Information The request has been successfully processed, but is returning information that may be from another source 204 No Content The request has been successfully processed, but is not returning any content 205 Reset Content The request has been successfully processed, but is not returning any content, and requires that the requester reset the document view 206 Partial Content The server is delivering only part of the resource due to a range header sent by the client 3xx: Redirection # Message Description Long Description 300 Multiple Choices A link list.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
