<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>encryption Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/encryption/</link>
    <description>Recent content in encryption Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/encryption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/encryption/getting-started-with-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/encryption/getting-started-with-encryption/</guid>
      <description>What is encryption? # In cryptography, encryption is the process of encoding messages or information in such a way that only authorized parties can access it.
Source: Encryption - Wikipedia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar cipher</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/encryption/caesar-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/encryption/caesar-cipher/</guid>
      <description>A Caesar cipher is one of the simplest and most widely known encryption techniques. The names comes from Julius Caesar, who, according to Suetonius, used it with a shift of three to protect messages of military significance
Encryption # Encyption happens by replacing each letter of the alfabet with an other letter. The keys can be showed with this circle. Here is a shift of 8 chars used.
Here will the A replaced by T, B by U, C by V etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text-to-text encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/encryption/text-to-text-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/encryption/text-to-text-encryption/</guid>
      <description>Modern cryptography operates on bytes, not text, so the output of cryptograhic algorithms is bytes. Sometimes encrypted data must be transferred via a text medium, and a binary-safe encoding must be used.
Parameters # Parameter Details TE Text Encoding. The transformation from text to bytes. UTF-8 is a common choice. BE Binary Encoding. A transform which is capable of processing any arbitrary data and producing a valid string. Base64 is the most commonly used encoding, with Base16/hexadecimal a good runner-up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
