<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>batch-file Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/batch-file/</link>
    <description>Recent content in batch-file Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/batch-file/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with batch-file</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/getting-started-with-batch-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/getting-started-with-batch-file/</guid>
      <description>Editing and Viewing Batch Files # Any ASCII editor can edit batch files. A list of editors that can syntax highlight batch syntax can be found here. You can also use the default notepad shipped with windows to edit and view a batch file, although it does not offer syntax highlighting.
To open notepad:
Press Win 𐌎+R, type notepad and then press Enter. Alternatively, the most &amp;ldquo;primitive&amp;rdquo; way to create a batch file is to redirect output from the command line to a file, eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variables in Batch Files</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/variables-in-batch-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/variables-in-batch-files/</guid>
      <description>Variable Substitution # Unlike other programming languages, in a batch file a variable is substituted by its actual value before the batch script is run. In other words, the substitution is made when the script is read into memory by the command processor, not when the script is later run.
This enables the use of variables as commands within the script, and as part of other variable names in the script, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between Batch (Windows) and Terminal (Linux)</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/differences-between-batch-windows-and-terminal-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/differences-between-batch-windows-and-terminal-linux/</guid>
      <description>Batch and bash are quite different. Batch flags are indicated with a /, while bash flags use a -. Capitalization matters in bash, but (almost) not at all in batch. Batch variable names can contain spaces, bash variable names can not.
Ultimately, both are ways of manipulating and interacting with the command line. Not surprisingly, there is a reasonably-sized amount of overlap between the capabilities of the two systems.
bitsadmin is deprecated in favor of the PowerShell cmdlet BITS but still works as of Windows 10 version 1607 certutil separates pairs of hexadecimal digits with a space, so md5sum will return an example value of d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e, while certutil displays the same value as d4 1d 8c d9 8f 00 b2 04 e9 80 09 98 ec f8 42 7e To cd to another drive (for example, from C: to D:) the /d flag must be used del can not delete folders, use rm instead grep is so much more powerful than find and findstr, it&amp;rsquo;s almost not fair to compare them; find has no regex capabilities and findstr has extremely limited regex capabilities ([a-z]{2} is not valid syntax, but [a-z][a-z] is) for loops on the Windows command prompt can only use single-character variable names; this is the only time batch variable names are case-sensitive for loops on the command prompt also use the variable form %A instead of %A% - forloops in batch scripts use the variable form %%A md automatically creates any necessary parent directories, while mkdir needs the -p flag to do so rem may not be used as an inline comment character unless it is preceded by a &amp;amp; :: may not be used as an inline comment at all, and should also not be used inside of a code block (set of parentheses) Note that some Windows command like ping still uses - as flags Batch Commands and Their Bash Equivalents # Batch Bash Description command /?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments in Batch Files</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/comments-in-batch-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/comments-in-batch-files/</guid>
      <description>Comments are used to show information in a batch script.
Syntax # REM
&amp;amp;REM
::
&amp;amp;::
Goto :Label
Comments. You can also use |&amp;gt;&amp;lt; ,etc. :Label
Using Labels as Comments # ::This is a label that acts as a comment The double-colon :: comment shown above is not documented as being a comment command, but it is a special case of a label that acts as a comment.
Caution: when labels are used as comments within a bracketed code block or for command, the command processor expects every label to be followed by at least one command, so when a jump is made to the label it will have something to execute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Loops in Batch Files</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/for-loops-in-batch-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/for-loops-in-batch-files/</guid>
      <description>Syntax # for /l %%p in (startNumber, increment, endNumber) do command for /f %%p in (filename) do command for /f %%p in (&amp;ldquo;textStrings&amp;rdquo;) do command for /f %%p in (&amp;lsquo;command&amp;rsquo;) do command for /r drive:\path %%p in (set) do command for /d %%p in (directory) do command The for command accepts options when the /f flag is used. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of options that can be used:
delims=x Delimiter character(s) to separate tokens</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/echo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/echo/</guid>
      <description>echo can be used to control and produce output.
Syntax # ECHO [ON | OFF] ECHO message ECHO(message ECHO( Parameters # Parameter Details ON | OFF Can either be ON or OFF (case insensitive) message Any string (except ON or OFF when used without () echo. will also display an empty string. However, this is slower than echo( as echo. will search for a file named &amp;ldquo;echo&amp;rdquo;. Only if this file does not exist will the command work, but this check makes it slower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Files using Batch</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/creating-files-using-batch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/creating-files-using-batch/</guid>
      <description>One useful feature of batch files is being able to create files with them. This section shows how to create files using batch code.
Syntax # echo (type here whatever you want in the to be) &amp;raquo; (filename) echo (variable name) &amp;raquo; (filename) If a file exists, &amp;gt; will overwrite the file and &amp;gt;&amp;gt; will append to the end of the file. If a file does not exist, both will create a new file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add delay to Batch file</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/add-delay-to-batch-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/add-delay-to-batch-file/</guid>
      <description>This topic will teach you one of the many useful things to know in the scripting language, batch file; Adding a delay/pause/timeout to your batch file.
Timeout # Timeout # The simplest way to make a delay or pause for a certain amount of time, is with the standard command TIMEOUT. To make a timeout that lasts exactly one minute we type:
timeout /t 60 Now what is going on here?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevated Privileges in Batch Files</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/elevated-privileges-in-batch-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/elevated-privileges-in-batch-files/</guid>
      <description>Requesting Elevate Privileges in a Shortcut # Many tasks require elevated privileges. You can elevate user privileges to Administrator level for your batch runtime using a shortcut:
Press alt+ and the batch file to a selected folder to create a shortcut.
Right click and select &amp;ldquo;Properties&amp;rdquo;.
Select the &amp;ldquo;Shortcut&amp;rdquo; tab.
Click &amp;ldquo;Advanced&amp;rdquo;.
Enable &amp;ldquo;Run as Administrator&amp;rdquo;.
Click &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; twice.
Requesting Elevated Privileges at Runtime # The following batch file will popup a UAC Prompt allowing you to accept elevated Administrator privileges for the batch session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch file command line arguments</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/batch-file-command-line-arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/batch-file/batch-file-command-line-arguments/</guid>
      <description>Batch files with more than 9 arguments # When more than 9 arguments are supplied, the shift [/n] command can be used, where /n means start at the nth argument, n is between zero and eight.
Looping through arguments:
:args set /a &amp;quot;i+=1&amp;quot; set arg!i!=%~1 call echo arg!i! = %%arg!i!%% shift goto :args Note, in the above example delayed expansion variable i is used to assign argument values to variables array.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
