<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>firebase-cloud-messaging Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/firebase-cloud-messaging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in firebase-cloud-messaging Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/firebase-cloud-messaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with firebase-cloud-messaging</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/firebase-cloud-messaging/getting-started-with-firebase-cloud-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/firebase-cloud-messaging/getting-started-with-firebase-cloud-messaging/</guid>
      <description>Installation or Setup # Firebase Cloud Messaging is the Firebase service that handles push notifications. You can add this service in any client: web, Android or IOS. The specific functioning for each must be read from the documentation.
For adding FCM in any type of project, is always adding a library.
Considering the special support for Android is worthy to take a few lines for it. Create a new project using Android Studio, in the menu go to Tools/Firebase, it will trigger the Firebase assistant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Cloud Messaging</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/firebase-cloud-messaging/firebase-cloud-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/firebase-cloud-messaging/firebase-cloud-messaging/</guid>
      <description>Firebase Cloud Messaging (FCM) is a cross-platform messaging solution that lets you reliably deliver messages at no cost.
Using FCM, you can notify a client app that new email or other data is available to sync. You can send notification messages to drive user reengagement and retention. For use cases such as instant messaging, a message can transfer a payload of up to 4KB to a client app.
Official Documentation: https://firebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Message Notifications</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/firebase-cloud-messaging/handling-message-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/firebase-cloud-messaging/handling-message-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Message handling on Android # Message handling on iOS # Message handling with app in background or killed # Firebase handles notifications differently when the app is in background (killed process) and when in foreground (active).
When your app is in the background, notification messages are displayed in the system tray, and onMessageReceived is not called. For notification messages with a data payload, the notification message is displayed in the system tray, and the data that was included with the notification message can be retrieved from the intent launched when the user taps on the notification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
