<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws-cli Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/aws-cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws-cli Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/aws-cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with aws-cli</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/getting-started-with-aws-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/getting-started-with-aws-cli/</guid>
      <description>Installation and setup # There are a number of different ways to install the AWS CLI on your machine, depending on what operating system and environment you are using:
On Microsoft Windows – use the MSI installer. On Linux, OS X, or Unix – use pip (a package manager for Python software) or install manually with the bundled installer.
Install using pip:
You will need python to be installed (version 2, 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aws-codecommit for local git</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/aws-codecommit-for-local-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/aws-codecommit-for-local-git/</guid>
      <description>Prepare by setting up your local development machine with the aws command line tool and the git command.
Setup Codecommit for git command line # AWS Codecommit can be used as storage for private GIT repositories. The setup involves a few steps, assuming you have a valid AWS account already.
Sign up for AWS Codecommit. Currently only region us-east-1 is available.
Create a IAM user who will have access to the repositories, eg codecommit-user</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ec2 describe-images usages</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/ec2-describe-images-usages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/ec2-describe-images-usages/</guid>
      <description>Describe image by AMI name # aws ec2 describe-images --filters &amp;quot;Name=name,Values=${NAME_OF_AMI}&amp;quot; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The --query Parameter</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/the---query-parameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/aws-cli/the---query-parameter/</guid>
      <description>The --query parameter is often overlooked, but it is incredibly powerful. It uses the JMESPath query language to filter service responses down to precisely what you want.
Listing Instances in an Easy to Read Way # Instances have a lot of metadata that gets returned from a call to describe-instances, but often times you just want to see the basics. You can use a JMESPath query combined with table output to show concise instance information in an easily readable way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
