<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>video Tutorial on </title>
    <link>https://www.wikiod.com/docs/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in video Tutorial on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.wikiod.com/docs/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with video</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/video/getting-started-with-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/video/getting-started-with-video/</guid>
      <description>Understanding stand-alone media files # The sample content used here is Tears of Steel, by Blender Foundation. Specifically, we will use the download titled &amp;ldquo;HD 720p (~365MB, mov, 2.0)&amp;rdquo;. This is a single file that ends with the extension &amp;ldquo;mov&amp;rdquo; and will play in just about any modern media player.
Note that the download page offers subtitles as separate SRT file downloads. In this sample content, there are no subtitles delivered together in the same file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding a media presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/video/understanding-a-media-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/video/understanding-a-media-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Video playback is front and center in a large range of modern solutions, with the software and standards evolving rapidly. To understand what makes up a media presentation, you must first understand the multiple aspects involved in working with video:
Raw color information captured from the physical world is commonly encoded using a codec - an algorithm whose purpose is to represent this data in a compressed form, often sacrificing some visual detail in favor of greater compression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video aspect ratios</title>
      <link>https://www.wikiod.com/video/video-aspect-ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wikiod.com/video/video-aspect-ratios/</guid>
      <description>Aspect ratios are often expressed as a width:height ratio which is often - but not always - simplified and sometimes also as a simple floating point integer.
All of the following aspect ratios are the same value expressed in different ways:
1280:720 16:9 1.7777777777777777777777777777778 Display aspect ratio (DAR) # This is a screenshot of a video playing. You see a normal 16:9 video like you would expect to see in any modern video solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
